<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<XMLDocContent PageName="cobalt.graphics.IVertexBuffer" Title="IVertexBuffer interface" xmlns="http://www.cobaltrenderer.com/schema/XMLDocSchema.xsd">
  <Paragraph>
    <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.Welcome">Home</PageRef> ->
    IVertexBuffer
  </Paragraph>
  <Section Title="Declaration">
    <Code Language="C++"><![CDATA[class IVertexBuffer;]]></Code>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Description">
    <Paragraph>
      The <TypeRef>IVertexBuffer</TypeRef> interface represents a buffer containing a set of vertex attributes, suitable
      to be bound as vertex shader inputs. Vertex attributes are specified by binding <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.VertexAttribute">VertexAttribute</PageRef>
      objects to the buffer through the <TypeRef>BindVertexAttribute</TypeRef> method, prior to calling the <TypeRef>AllocateMemory</TypeRef>
      method. Once the <TypeRef>AllocateMemory</TypeRef> method has been called, the layout and size of the buffer has
      been fixed, and cannot be changed. Multiple vertex attributes can be bound to the same buffer. Renderable objects
      can use any attributes from any set of buffers, there is no requirement that all vertex attributes for a single
      object must come from a single buffer.
    </Paragraph>
    <Note Type="Important">
      <Paragraph>
        Buffers may be created either in automatic or manual layout mode. Automatic layout buffers are free to allocate
        memory using whatever memory layout the renderer determines is optimal, and are easiest for applications to work
        with. Automatic layout buffers cannot be modified directly, instead the contents of the buffer are set and
        updated through the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.VertexAttribute.SetInitialData">SetInitialData</PageRef> and
        <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.VertexAttribute.QueueDataUpdate">QueueDataUpdate</PageRef> methods on the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.VertexAttribute">VertexAttribute</PageRef>
        objects which are bound to them. Manual layout buffers on the other hand require the application to explicitly
        specify starting location and stride of each attribute. With the layout explicitly defined however, applications
        are able to manually write to the buffer using the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IVertexBuffer.SetRawInitialData">SetRawInitialData</PageRef>
        and <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IVertexBuffer.QueueRawDataUpdate">QueueRawDataUpdate</PageRef> methods,
        potentially updating the contents of multiple attributes at once. Additionally, an alias of the buffer can be
        created using the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IVertexBuffer.AllocateMemoryWithAlias">AllocateMemoryWithAlias</PageRef>
        method, allowing the buffer to be directly written to in shaders, such as a compute shader. To allocate a buffer
        in automatic layout mode, attach attributes using the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IVertexBuffer.BindVertexAttribute">BindVertexAttribute</PageRef>
        method. To allocate a buffer in manual layout mode, attach attributes using the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IVertexBuffer.BindVertexAttributeManualLayout">BindVertexAttributeManualLayout</PageRef>
        method. Unless you require the features provided by manual layout mode, it is recommended to use automatic
        layout buffers.
      </Paragraph>
    </Note>
    <Note Type="Important">
      <Paragraph>
        Note that a single vertex buffer does not necessarily correspond with a single block of allocated memory of the
        requested size in hardware. Renderers are free to manage physical memory allocation in any way they see fit, and
        may split or combine buffers, or create multiple buffers for purposes such as staging changes or swapping buffers
        between frames. From the application perspective, buffers should be defined that group sets of vertex attributes
        together that are logically related, and that are expected to be used together, and especially modified together
        or deleted together.
      </Paragraph>
    </Note>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Members">
    <SubSection Title="Initialization methods">
      <FunctionMemberList>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="Delete" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IVertexBuffer.Delete">
          Schedules the object for deletion. After calling this method, the object will be destroyed after the current
          frame completes drawing.
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="AllocateMemory" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IVertexBuffer.AllocateMemory">
          Attempts to allocate memory for the buffer using the supplied set of vertex attributes
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="AllocateMemoryWithAlias" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IVertexBuffer.AllocateMemoryWithAlias">
          Attempts to allocate memory for the buffer, and alias it with an <PageRef PageName ="cobalt.graphics.ITexelArray">ITexelArray</PageRef>.
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
      </FunctionMemberList>
    </SubSection>
    <SubSection Title="Binding methods">
      <FunctionMemberList>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="BindVertexAttribute" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IVertexBuffer.BindVertexAttribute">
          Binds the specified <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.VertexAttribute">VertexAttribute</PageRef> as a member of the buffer
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="BindVertexAttributeManualLayout" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IVertexBuffer.BindVertexAttributeManualLayout">
          Binds the specified <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.VertexAttribute">VertexAttribute</PageRef> as a member
          of the buffer, with a manually defined buffer offset and stride.
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
      </FunctionMemberList>
    </SubSection>
    <SubSection Title="Data methods">
      <FunctionMemberList>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="SetRawInitialData" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IVertexBuffer.SetRawInitialData">
          Allows initial data to be set directly for the buffer where manual layout attributes have been bound with the
          <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IVertexBuffer.BindVertexAttributeManualLayout">BindVertexAttributeManualLayout</PageRef> method.
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="QueueRawDataUpdate" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IVertexBuffer.QueueRawDataUpdate">
          Allows data to be written directly to the buffer where manual layout attributes have been bound with the
          <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IVertexBuffer.BindVertexAttributeManualLayout">BindVertexAttributeManualLayout</PageRef> method.
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
      </FunctionMemberList>
    </SubSection>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="See also">
    <PageRefList>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.VertexAttribute">VertexAttribute</PageRefListEntry>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.IIndexBuffer">IIndexBuffer</PageRefListEntry>
    </PageRefList>
  </Section>
</XMLDocContent>
