<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<XMLDocContent PageName="cobalt.graphics.ITextureBuffer.IsSampleCountSupported" Title="IsSampleCountSupported method" xmlns="http://www.cobaltrenderer.com/schema/XMLDocSchema.xsd">
  <Paragraph>
    <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.Welcome">Home</PageRef> ->
    <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.ITextureBuffer">ITextureBuffer</PageRef> ->
    IsSampleCountSupported
  </Paragraph>
  <Section Title="Description">
    <Paragraph>
      The <TypeRef>IsSampleCountSupported</TypeRef> method returns true if the current renderer and graphics device can
      create a two dimensional multisampled texture using the supplied image format, data format, and sample count. This
      is intended for testing multisample anti-aliasing (MSAA) framebuffer attachment support before calling
      <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.ITextureBuffer.SetSampleCount">SetSampleCount</PageRef> and
      <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.ITextureBuffer.AllocateMemory">AllocateMemory</PageRef>.
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph>
      The query uses the supplied arguments directly, rather than inspecting the texture object's current format,
      dimensions, sample count, or allocation state. It can therefore be called before any texture format has been set,
      or on a texture object that has already been created and used. The check assumes a two dimensional texture with a
      single mipmap level.
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph>
      Renderer backends evaluate support through their native graphics API. If the renderer would select a compatible
      fallback allocation format for the requested image and data format combination, support is checked against the
      native format that would actually be used.
    </Paragraph>
    <Note Type="Important">
      <Paragraph>
        This method is only available on <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.ITextureBuffer2D">ITextureBuffer2D</PageRef>
        objects. A false return value is not an error; it means the requested MSAA texture configuration is not
        available on the current renderer and graphics device.
      </Paragraph>
    </Note>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Usage">
    <Code Language="C++"><![CDATA[bool IsSampleCountSupported(ImageFormat imageFormat, DataFormat dataFormat, SampleCount sampleCount) const;]]></Code>
    <SubSection Title="Argument list">
      <ArgumentList>
        <ArgumentListEntry Type="ImageFormat!cobalt.graphics.ITextureBuffer.ImageFormat" Name="imageFormat">
          The image format to test for the multisampled two dimensional texture.
        </ArgumentListEntry>
        <ArgumentListEntry Type="DataFormat!cobalt.graphics.ITextureBuffer.DataFormat" Name="dataFormat">
          The data format to test for the multisampled two dimensional texture.
        </ArgumentListEntry>
        <ArgumentListEntry Type="SampleCount!cobalt.graphics.ITextureBuffer.SampleCount" Name="sampleCount">
          The number of samples to test for each pixel of the two dimensional texture.
        </ArgumentListEntry>
      </ArgumentList>
    </SubSection>
    <SubSection Title="Return value">
      <Paragraph>
        Returns true if the current renderer and graphics device report support for the requested texture configuration,
        or false if that combination cannot be used.
      </Paragraph>
    </SubSection>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="See also">
    <PageRefList>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.ITextureBuffer.SampleCount">ITextureBuffer.SampleCount</PageRefListEntry>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.ITextureBuffer.SetSampleCount">ITextureBuffer.SetSampleCount</PageRefListEntry>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.ITextureBuffer2D">ITextureBuffer2D</PageRefListEntry>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.IFrameBuffer.BindTexture">IFrameBuffer.BindTexture</PageRefListEntry>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.IFrameBuffer.BindMultiSamplingResolveTexture">IFrameBuffer.BindMultiSamplingResolveTexture</PageRefListEntry>
    </PageRefList>
  </Section>
</XMLDocContent>
