<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<XMLDocContent PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDevice.MemoryType" Title="MemoryType enumeration" xmlns="http://www.cobaltrenderer.com/schema/XMLDocSchema.xsd">
  <Paragraph>
    <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.Welcome">Home</PageRef> ->
    <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDevice">IGraphicsDevice</PageRef> ->
    MemoryType
  </Paragraph>
  <Section Title="Description">
    <Paragraph>
      The <TypeRef>MemoryType</TypeRef> enumeration is used to distinguish between different classes of memory available
      to a <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDevice">IGraphicsDevice</PageRef> object, as used when calling
      the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDevice.GetMemorySizeInBytes">GetMemorySizeInBytes</PageRef>
      method.
    </Paragraph>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Members">
    <EnumMemberList>
      <EnumMemberListEntry Name="Dedicated">
        This category includes all physical memory which is exclusively owned by the graphics device itself, such that
        if the graphics device was removed this memory would also no longer be available. It is important to note that
        dedicated memory is not necessarily totally unaccessible to other parts of the system, as graphics devices
        commonly have ways of mapping at least parts of their dedicated memory in a manner that makes it accessible to
        the rest of the system, to help facilitate data transfers, but if the graphics device physically holds or
        contains the memory, or is exclusively responsible for making it available to other devices in the system, the
        memory is considered dedicated memory.
      </EnumMemberListEntry>
      <EnumMemberListEntry Name="Shared">
        Shared memory is any memory which is not exclusively owned by the graphics device. Integrated graphics devices
        typically make extensive use of shared memory, such as being apportioned a section of general system memory by
        the memory controller in a fixed manner, or in a configurable manner via the BIOS. Note however that integrated
        devices may also have dedicated physical memory on-die. Under some system environments, dedicated graphics
        devices also make extensive or exclusive use of shared memory. This has occurred on some major game console such
        as the original Xbox, and is also common on mobile and embedded systems, however generally discrete graphics
        devices will make use of dedicated memory, as this is often capable of yielding better rendering performance,
        perhaps with a trade-off of increased times upload data to the graphics device.
      </EnumMemberListEntry>
    </EnumMemberList>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="See also">
    <PageRefList>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDevice">IGraphicsDevice</PageRefListEntry>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDevice.GetMemorySizeInBytes">IGraphicsDevice.GetMemorySizeInBytes</PageRefListEntry>
    </PageRefList>
  </Section>
</XMLDocContent>
