<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<XMLDocContent PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDevice.Vendor" Title="Vendor enumeration" xmlns="http://www.cobaltrenderer.com/schema/XMLDocSchema.xsd">
  <Paragraph>
    <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.Welcome">Home</PageRef> ->
    <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDevice">IGraphicsDevice</PageRef> ->
    Vendor
  </Paragraph>
  <Section Title="Description">
    <Paragraph>
      The <TypeRef>Vendor</TypeRef> enumeration is used to report the vendor associated with the graphics device
      represented by a given <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDevice">IGraphicsDevice</PageRef>, as returned
      by the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDevice.GetVendor">GetVendor</PageRef> method. In most cases,
      this identifies the vendor who designed the graphics processor. In some cases, it may identify a software or
      driver stack instead, such as a device exposed through Mesa.
    </Paragraph>
    <Note Type="Important">
      <Paragraph>
        It is not recommended to alter the behaviour of your application in any meaningful way based on the vendor
        alone. Instead, you should rely on reported characteristics of the device, such as supported features, in order
        to make decisions on how your program uses the hardware, as new devices by a given vendor may be significantly
        different to previous devices they have released. Information on vendor is provided for informational purposes
        only, such as for reporting or displaying information to the user.
      </Paragraph>
    </Note>
    <Note Type="Important">
      <Paragraph>
        As this enumeration is a fixed set of known vendors, it will not be able to return accurate vendor information
        on exotic or custom graphics devices by unknown manufacturers. In these cases, the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDevice.GetVendorName">GetVendorName</PageRef>
        method may be able to provide more information.
      </Paragraph>
    </Note>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Members">
    <EnumMemberList>
      <EnumMemberListEntry Name="AMD">
        The device is reported as using a graphics processor or driver stack from Advanced Micro Devices.
      </EnumMemberListEntry>
      <EnumMemberListEntry Name="ImgTec">
        The device is reported as using a graphics processor or driver stack from Imagination Technologies.
      </EnumMemberListEntry>
      <EnumMemberListEntry Name="Nvidia">
        The device is reported as using a graphics processor or driver stack from NVIDIA.
      </EnumMemberListEntry>
      <EnumMemberListEntry Name="ARM">
        The device is reported as using a graphics processor or driver stack from ARM.
      </EnumMemberListEntry>
      <EnumMemberListEntry Name="Microsoft">
        The device is reported as using a graphics processor or driver stack from Microsoft, such as a software or
        platform-provided adapter.
      </EnumMemberListEntry>
      <EnumMemberListEntry Name="Qualcomm">
        The device is reported as using a graphics processor or driver stack from Qualcomm.
      </EnumMemberListEntry>
      <EnumMemberListEntry Name="Intel">
        The device is reported as using a graphics processor or driver stack from Intel.
      </EnumMemberListEntry>
      <EnumMemberListEntry Name="Apple">
        The device is reported as using a graphics processor or driver stack from Apple.
      </EnumMemberListEntry>
      <EnumMemberListEntry Name="Mesa">
        The device is reported as being exposed through the Mesa graphics stack.
      </EnumMemberListEntry>
      <EnumMemberListEntry Name="Vivante">
        The device is reported as using a graphics processor or driver stack from Vivante.
      </EnumMemberListEntry>
      <EnumMemberListEntry Name="VeriSilicon">
        The device is reported as using a graphics processor or driver stack from VeriSilicon.
      </EnumMemberListEntry>
      <EnumMemberListEntry Name="Unknown">
        The vendor associated with the device couldn't be determined, or could not be matched to one of the known
        entries in this enumeration. In this case, <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDevice.GetVendorName">GetVendorName</PageRef>
        may still be able to return a textual vendor name reported by the graphics API or driver.
      </EnumMemberListEntry>
    </EnumMemberList>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="See also">
    <PageRefList>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDevice">IGraphicsDevice</PageRefListEntry>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDevice.GetVendor">IGraphicsDevice.GetVendor</PageRefListEntry>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDevice.GetVendorName">IGraphicsDevice.GetVendorName</PageRefListEntry>
    </PageRefList>
  </Section>
</XMLDocContent>
