<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<XMLDocContent PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDevice.GetMemorySizeInBytes" Title="GetMemorySizeInBytes method" xmlns="http://www.cobaltrenderer.com/schema/XMLDocSchema.xsd">
  <Paragraph>
    <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.Welcome">Home</PageRef> ->
    <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDevice">IGraphicsDevice</PageRef> ->
    GetMemorySizeInBytes
  </Paragraph>
  <Section Title="Description">
    <Paragraph>
      The <TypeRef>GetMemorySizeInBytes</TypeRef> method returns the size of the requested type of memory in bytes, as
      reported by the graphics driver.
    </Paragraph>
    <Note Type="Warning">
      <Paragraph>
        The renderer is entirely dependent on request features in the underlying graphics API to retrieve this
        information, and that is in tern entirely dependent on the reported values from the graphics driver. It has been
        observed that is frequent for graphics drivers to report inaccurate information about their memory totals. This
        may have been done deliberately under older APIs where 32-bit integer limits started presenting problems for
        devices as memory sizes reached the 2GB and 4GB thresholds. The various graphics APIs also have problems with
        ambiguities on how memory totals should be reported, especially where there are different types of dedicated
        memory, such as a dedicated upload heap. It is common to see significant variation between reported memory
        totals for the same device between different graphics APIs. The totals reported on newer generation APIs such
        as Vulkan and Direct3D 12 are generally more reliable than older APIs such as OpenGL, however it is advised not
        to rely on these numbers too heavily in your application. It may be appropriate to examine the reported memory
        totals when making relative judgements on the best graphics device to select, however caution is advised when
        attempting to use these numbers for anything other than reporting purposes.
      </Paragraph>
    </Note>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Usage">
    <Code Language="C++"><![CDATA[size_t GetMemorySizeInBytes(MemoryType memoryType) const;]]></Code>
    <SubSection Title="Argument list">
      <ArgumentList>
        <ArgumentListEntry Type="MemoryType!cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDevice.MemoryType" Name="type">
          The type of the memory to query the size of
        </ArgumentListEntry>
      </ArgumentList>
    </SubSection>
    <SubSection Title="Return value">
      <ReturnValue Type="size_t">
        The size of the requested memory type in 8-bit bytes
      </ReturnValue>
    </SubSection>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="See also">
    <PageRefList>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDevice">IGraphicsDevice</PageRefListEntry>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDevice.GetVendorName">IGraphicsDevice.GetVendorName</PageRefListEntry>
    </PageRefList>
  </Section>
</XMLDocContent>
