<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<XMLDocContent PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDevice.GetVendor" Title="GetVendor method" xmlns="http://www.cobaltrenderer.com/schema/XMLDocSchema.xsd">
  <Paragraph>
    <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.Welcome">Home</PageRef> ->
    <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDevice">IGraphicsDevice</PageRef> ->
    GetVendor
  </Paragraph>
  <Section Title="Description">
    <Paragraph>
      The <TypeRef>GetVendor</TypeRef> method returns an entry from the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDevice.Vendor">Vendor</PageRef>
      enumeration, indicating the known vendor associated with the graphics device. Where a device is powered by a
      chipset designed by one manufacturer, but on a custom board designed and assembled by another, this will usually
      be the name of the chipset manufacturer. For example, a graphics card manufactured by Leadtek, but powered by an
      NVIDIA GPU, would report NVIDIA as the vendor. In some cases, the reported vendor may identify a software or
      driver stack instead of a hardware manufacturer.
    </Paragraph>
    <Note Type="Important">
      <Paragraph>
        Where the vendor cannot be determined, or the vendor is not included in the enumeration as a known common
        vendor, the <TypeRef>Unknown</TypeRef> enumeration entry will be returned instead. In this case, the
        <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDevice.GetVendorName">GetVendorName</PageRef> method may be able to
        return a string representing the name of the vendor.
      </Paragraph>
    </Note>
    <Note Type="Important">
      <Paragraph>
        It is not recommended to alter the behaviour of your application in any meaningful way based on the vendor
        alone. Instead, you should rely on reported characteristics of the device, such as supported features, in order
        to make decisions on how your program uses the hardware, as new devices by a given vendor may be significantly
        different to previous devices they have released. Information on vendor is provided for informational purposes
        only, such as for reporting or displaying information to the user.
      </Paragraph>
    </Note>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Usage">
    <Code Language="C++"><![CDATA[Vendor GetVendor() const;]]></Code>
    <SubSection Title="Return value">
      <ReturnValue Type="Vendor!cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDevice.Vendor">
        The vendor associated with the device as reported by the graphics driver.
      </ReturnValue>
    </SubSection>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="See also">
    <PageRefList>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDevice">IGraphicsDevice</PageRefListEntry>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDevice.GetVendorName">IGraphicsDevice.GetVendorName</PageRefListEntry>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDevice.GetDeviceName">IGraphicsDevice.GetDeviceName</PageRefListEntry>
    </PageRefList>
  </Section>
</XMLDocContent>
