<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<XMLDocContent PageName="cobalt.graphics.Welcome" Title="Cobalt Renderer SDK" xmlns="http://www.cobaltrenderer.com/schema/XMLDocSchema.xsd">
  <Section Title="What is the Cobalt Renderer?">
    <Paragraph>
      The Cobalt Renderer is a generic, cross-platform API, intended for use in any application requiring access to 3D graphics hardware. It
      is a modern, light-weight, interface-based library, which unifies concepts and features across all available graphics APIs, and
      presents them in a consistent, easily accessible form. Renderer plugins implement the Cobalt API on top of native APIs such Direct3D,
      OpenGL, Vulkan, and Metal (coming soon). These plugins are designed to be lightweight and low overhead, while enabling advanced
      optimisations that would be difficult to achieve at the application level. The Cobalt Renderer was Originally developed in 2019-2020 as
      an internal library for a range of commercial software. As of 2026, this library is now available for free as an open-source project
      under the permissive MIT license.
    </Paragraph>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Why does this exist?">
    <Paragraph>
      The Cobalt Renderer aims to make using modern 3D graphics hardware simple. It does this by giving you a clean clean API to express
      what you want to draw (or compute), without getting bogged down in how to do that.
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph>
      From around 2005, 3D graphics hardware has in many ways gotten simpler, while conversely, graphics APIs have exploded in complexity.
      What took a few dozen lines of code to express in OpenGL in 1996 now takes a few thousand lines of code on any modern graphics API. At
      the same time, the games industry, the primary driver of advances in 3D graphics hardware, has consolidated around a handful of large
      engines and middleware packages. Graphics APIs now primarily cater to the interests of these engines, which want the lowest level,
      most direct access to the hardware possible. Modern graphics APIs require you to worry about issues like memory residency, shared vs
      separate command queues, or differences between unified vs discrete video memory, which while great for micro-optimizing a game engine
      on console hardware with known fixed system specs, makes it virtually impossible to just draw a few simple polygons to the screen in a
      standalone product, especially on PC hardware with a wide range of graphics devices with differing capabilities. As graphics hardware
      and APIs continue to change and evolve, there's also a significant maintainenance burden keeping code that drives low-level graphics
      APIs current.
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph>
      The Cobalt Renderer addresses these issues by remaining focused on the high-level of what you're actually trying to do, giving you a
      natural way of expressing that in a way that isn't platform or API dependent. You have full control over your draw/compute operations,
      with full flexibility to define your shaders the way you want, but all the "glue" of setting up the hardware, putting everything into
      the correct state, and moving data around or synchronizing changes between shader stages is handled for you. The Cobalt Renderer
      understands what you want to do at a high enough level to ensure this all happens at the right time, in the right order, using the
      most efficient techniques on each underlying API, to achieve the best possible performance. Additionally, shader cross-compilation is
      built in, allowing you to write your shader code once in one format, such as HLSL or compiled SPIR-V, and run that code on any
      platform, with any underlying renderer API. This makes it possible to put a polygon on the screen with a few dozen lines of code
      again, while still allowing you to do incredibly demanding drawing tasks at speed and scale, with better performance than you would be
      likely to achieve even if you did it all yourself by hand.
    </Paragraph>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="What ISN'T the Cobalt Renderer?">
    <Paragraph>
      1. Not a full engine/framework. The Cobalt Renderer just does rendering. It doesn't handle collision detection, physics, scripting,
      asset formats, audio, input handling, or anything else of that nature. If you're looking for a solution which covers those areas, you
      should look at other packages which cater for that, such as a game engine. The Cobalt Renderer could theoretically be used as a
      component within a game engine, but its focus is 100% on rendering/compute alone.
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph>
      2. Not limited to game development. The Cobalt Renderer is not built for any one specific task. It is built to drive tasks on modern
      3D graphics hardware. That could be realtime gaming. It could also be event-driven CAD software, or cloud-based graphics rendering, or
      data analytics, or pure GPU compute. It doesn't assume you're doing any kind of specific task. This makes it flexible and useful as a
      component in a wide variety of areas, including, game development, but it's not built assuming that's what you will be doing.
    </Paragraph>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Philosophy">
    <List>
      <ListEntry>
        <TypeRef>Simplicity over squeezing performance.</TypeRef>
        A maintainable and clear architecture is more important than chasing a marginal improvement in performance.
      </ListEntry>
      <ListEntry>
        <TypeRef>Keep a clean and expressive interface.</TypeRef>
        The API should have clear naming with no superfluous functionality.
      </ListEntry>
      <ListEntry>
        <TypeRef>Distill the core functionality of underlying APIs.</TypeRef>
        Various characteristics from each API should be focused to their common elements.
      </ListEntry>
      <ListEntry>
        <TypeRef>Implement established technologies.</TypeRef>
        Only implement functionality and extensions with strong cross-vendor adoption.
      </ListEntry>
    </List>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Packages">
    <Paragraph>
      The Renderer SDK contains a set of header-only libraries and APIs, split into separate subdirectories. While there are many
      header files contained in each directory, there are special "package" headers with a .pkg extension, which are the only header
      files that are intended to be directly included by applications. The most important package is this:
    </Paragraph>
    <Code Language="C++"><![CDATA[#include <Cobalt/RendererInterface/RendererInterface.pkg>]]></Code>
    <Paragraph>
      <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.RendererInterface">RendererInterface.pkg</PageRef> contains the
      core platform-independent graphics API, covering devices, renderers, render tree nodes, resources, shader
      programs, and so on. This is the only header you will need to include for most of your code. Additionally, there is the
      following package:
    </Paragraph>
    <Code Language="C++"><![CDATA[#include <Cobalt/RendererInterface/PlatformBindings.pkg>]]></Code>
    <Paragraph>
      <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.PlatformBindings">PlatformBindings.pkg</PageRef> contains
      the platform-specific support types and helpers needed to load renderer plugins and connect the renderer to native
      window systems. Note that this package will include platform-specific system header files, which are deliberately kept out of
      <TypeRef>RendererInterface.pkg</TypeRef>. This will only be needed where you perform plugin discovery, and where you bind actual
      OS windows/surfaces to framebuffers. You will also need to include the following:
    </Paragraph>
    <Code Language="C++"><![CDATA[#include <Cobalt/Logging/Logging.pkg>]]></Code>
    <Paragraph>
      <PageRef PageName="cobalt.logging.Welcome">Logging.pkg</PageRef> is required at the point where you create the
      <PageRef PageName="cobalt.logging.LogManager">LogManager</PageRef> for the renderer, which is the first step prior to performing
      any other tasks. No other headers should need to be manually included.
    </Paragraph>
    <PageRefList>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.RendererInterface">RendererInterface package</PageRefListEntry>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.PlatformBindings">PlatformBindings package</PageRefListEntry>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.logging.Welcome">Logging system</PageRefListEntry>
    </PageRefList>
  </Section>
</XMLDocContent>
