<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<XMLDocContent PageName="cobalt.graphics.IDataArray" Title="IDataArray interface" xmlns="http://www.cobaltrenderer.com/schema/XMLDocSchema.xsd">
  <Paragraph>
    <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.Welcome">Home</PageRef> ->
    IDataArray
  </Paragraph>
  <Section Title="Declaration">
    <Code Language="C++"><![CDATA[class IDataArray;]]></Code>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Description">
    <Paragraph>
      The <TypeRef>IDataArray</TypeRef> interface defines an array of one or more data structures. This maps to the
      concept of the <TypeRef>StructuredBuffer</TypeRef>/<TypeRef>RWStructuredBuffer</TypeRef> types in the HLSL shader
      language. Additionally, an <TypeRef>IDataArray</TypeRef> supports an attached atomic counter value which can be
      atomically modified within shaders, and easily reset and read back on the CPU. The <TypeRef>IDataArray</TypeRef>
      type is also able to act as a source for indirect draw parameters, making it ideal as a buffer to write to from a
      compute shader for indirect drawing. Low-level atomic operations are also supported on regions of an <TypeRef>IDataArray</TypeRef>.
      When used with atomic operations or for indirect drawing, the <TypeRef>ByteAddressBuffer</TypeRef>/<TypeRef>RWByteAddressBuffer</TypeRef>
      HLSL shader types must be used instead. It is also possible to schedule a transfer from one <TypeRef>IDataArray</TypeRef>
      to another entirely on the GPU using the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IDataArray.QueueDataTransfer">QueueDataTransfer</PageRef>
      method.
    </Paragraph>
    <Note Type="Important">
      <Paragraph>
        There are similarities between the <TypeRef>IDataArray</TypeRef> and the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.ITexelArray">ITexelArray</PageRef>
        type. Both define potentially very large buffers of data, which can be read and written from both shaders and the
        CPU. There are distinct differences however. The <TypeRef>ITexelArray</TypeRef> type defines a regular array of
        vectors, with a specific list of supported types. Because the type is explicit and known by the hardware,
        automatic format conversion is supported for many data types when reading or writing from shaders. Additionally,
        an <TypeRef>ITexelArray</TypeRef> is able to alias an <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IIndexBuffer">IIndexBuffer</PageRef>
        or an <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IVertexBuffer">IVertexBuffer</PageRef>, allowing these buffers to be
        written from a shader, such as a compute shader. The <TypeRef>IDataArray</TypeRef> type on the other hand contains
        an array of structures, which are an arbitrary block of bytes. These data structures can be mapped to complex
        struct types within your shader, allowing a potentially large collection of differing types of values to be easily
        encoded in each entry of the array. The opaque nature of these structures to hardware however, means no automatic
        format conversion is possible, nor is it possible to alias an <TypeRef>IIndexBuffer</TypeRef> or <TypeRef>IVertexBuffer</TypeRef>.
        On the other hand, <TypeRef>IDataArray</TypeRef> can be used to perform indirect drawing, and atomic memory
        operations within shaders. You should consider the structure of your data and the features required, and select
        the array type which best fits your usage.
      </Paragraph>
    </Note>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Enumerations">
    <TypeMemberList>
      <TypeMemberListEntry Name="UsageFlags" TypeCategory="Enumeration" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IDataArray.UsageFlags" Visibility="Public">
        Flags to inform the renderer on how this data array will be used
      </TypeMemberListEntry>
    </TypeMemberList>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Enumerations (Inherited from IResourceArray)">
    <TypeMemberList>
      <TypeMemberListEntry Name="PerformanceHint" TypeCategory="Enumeration" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IResourceArray.PerformanceHint" Visibility="Public">
        Flags to provide hints to the graphics system about how the application will use this buffer. Correct use of
        performance hints allows the renderer to optimize the way the data is stored and modified to give the best
        performance.
      </TypeMemberListEntry>
      <TypeMemberListEntry Name="DataPersistenceFlags" TypeCategory="Enumeration" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IResourceArray.DataPersistenceFlags" Visibility="Public">
        Flags to provide hints to the graphics system about the required lifetime of data stored in this buffer. These
        flags can be used to reduce memory requirements or increase performance in some circumstances.
      </TypeMemberListEntry>
    </TypeMemberList>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Members">
    <SubSection Title="Initialization methods">
      <FunctionMemberList>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="Delete" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IDataArray.Delete">
          Schedules the object for deletion. After calling this method, the object will be destroyed after the current
          frame completes drawing.
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="AllocateMemory" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IDataArray.AllocateMemory">
          Attempts to allocate memory for the buffer using the defined buffer layout and page settings
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="SetBufferLayout" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IDataArray.SetBufferLayout">
          Defines the layout of the buffer, and whether it has an attached counter. Must be set before calling <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IDataArray.AllocateMemory">AllocateMemory</PageRef>.
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
      </FunctionMemberList>
    </SubSection>
    <SubSection Title="Usage methods">
      <FunctionMemberList>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="SetUsageFlags" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IDataArray.SetUsageFlags">
          Informs the renderer on how this buffer will be used. Certain operations are disallowed unless usage flags
          have been set to inform the renderer in advance that those operations may be requested.
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
      </FunctionMemberList>
    </SubSection>
    <SubSection Title="Usage methods (Inherited from IResourceArray)">
      <FunctionMemberList>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="SetPerformanceHints" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IResourceArray.SetPerformanceHints">
          Provides hints to the renderer about how this object will be used. Correct use of hints is important to optimize performance.
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="SetDataPersistenceFlags" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IResourceArray.SetDataPersistenceFlags">
          Provides hints to the graphics system about the required lifetime of data stored in this buffer. This can be
          used to reduce memory requirements or increase performance in some circumstances.
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
      </FunctionMemberList>
    </SubSection>
    <SubSection Title="Data methods">
      <FunctionMemberList>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="SetInitialData" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IDataArray.SetInitialData">
          Supplies initial data to use when allocating the buffer. Note that the supplied memory must remain valid and
          accessible until the <TypeRef>AllocateMemory</TypeRef> method is called.
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="QueueDataUpdate" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IDataArray.QueueDataUpdate">
          Updates data in the buffer. Unlike the <TypeRef>SetInitialData</TypeRef> method, the provided memory can be
          modified or deallocated immediately after this method returns.
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="QueueDataTransfer" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IDataArray.QueueDataTransfer">
          Schedules a transfer from one <TypeRef>IDataArray</TypeRef> to another, within GPU memory.
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="UpdateCounterResetValue" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IDataArray.UpdateCounterResetValue">
          Modifies the reset value to use for the counter, if the buffer has been created with one attached.
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
      </FunctionMemberList>
    </SubSection>
    <SubSection Title="Output capture methods">
      <FunctionMemberList>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="AddOutputCaptureTarget" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IDataArray.AddOutputCaptureTarget">
          Adds the specified output capture target to this data array. This allows data written to the array from within
          shader programs to be retrieved by the application.
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="RemoveOutputCaptureTarget" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IDataArray.RemoveOutputCaptureTarget">
          Removes the specified output capture target from this data array.
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
      </FunctionMemberList>
    </SubSection>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="See also">
    <PageRefList>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.IDataArrayOutput">IDataArrayOutput</PageRefListEntry>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.ITexelArray">ITexelArray</PageRefListEntry>
    </PageRefList>
  </Section>
</XMLDocContent>
