<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<XMLDocContent PageName="cobalt.marshalling.MarshallableDelete" Title="MarshallableDelete" xmlns="http://www.cobaltrenderer.com/schema/XMLDocSchema.xsd">
  <Section Title="Declaration">
    <Code Language="C++"><![CDATA[template<class T>
class MarshallableDelete;

template<class T>
class MarshallableDelete<T[]>;]]></Code>
  </Section>

  <Section Title="Description">
    <Paragraph>
      The <TypeRef>MarshallableDelete</TypeRef> helper provides a custom deleter suitable for use with <TypeRef>std::unique_ptr</TypeRef> when a pointer
      needs to cross an assembly boundary but must still be deleted from the assembly that originally created it. The deleter stores a small shared
      reference-counted helper object, which keeps the actual delete operation anchored to the originating module. The <TypeRef>MarshallableDelete&lt;T[]&gt;</TypeRef>
      specialization performs the corresponding array deletion with <TypeRef>delete[]</TypeRef>.
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph>
      This helper is only available when C++11 support is enabled, as it relies on <TypeRef>std::unique_ptr</TypeRef>. It is intended for the common case
      where an interface or other marshallable object uses RAII ownership, but the allocation and destruction must still happen on the same heap.
    </Paragraph>
  </Section>

  <Section Title="Members">
    <SubSection Title="Constructors">
      <Paragraph>
        The helper is default-constructible and copyable. Copying the deleter shares ownership of the internal reference-counted helper object, so all
        copies delete through the same originating assembly.
      </Paragraph>
    </SubSection>
    <SubSection Title="Function operator">
      <Paragraph>
        Calling the function operator deletes the supplied pointer using the appropriate delete expression for the specialization being used.
      </Paragraph>
    </SubSection>
  </Section>

  <Section Title="Usage">
    <Paragraph>
      Use <TypeRef>MarshallableDelete</TypeRef> as the deleter argument for <TypeRef>std::unique_ptr</TypeRef> when returning ownership of marshallable
      objects across a module boundary.
    </Paragraph>
    <Code Language="C++"><![CDATA[std::unique_ptr<IPalette, cobalt::marshalling::MarshallableDelete<IPalette>> CreatePaletteObject();]]></Code>
  </Section>

  <Section Title="See also">
    <PageRefList>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.marshalling.Concepts.InterfaceDesign">Interface Design</PageRefListEntry>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.marshalling.Concepts.MarshallingSTL">Marshalling STL Types</PageRefListEntry>
    </PageRefList>
  </Section>
</XMLDocContent>
