<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<XMLDocContent PageName="cobalt.graphics.IStateBuffer" Title="IStateBuffer interface" xmlns="http://www.cobaltrenderer.com/schema/XMLDocSchema.xsd">
  <Paragraph>
    <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.Welcome">Home</PageRef> ->
    IStateBuffer
  </Paragraph>
  <Section Title="Declaration">
    <Code Language="C++"><![CDATA[class IStateBuffer;]]></Code>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Description">
    <Paragraph>
      The <TypeRef>IStateBuffer</TypeRef> interface defines a state buffer for use in a shader program. State buffers
      are a block of memory that can contain multiple state values, and can be mapped into multiple shaders at once.
      Although like global state values they are still read-only within a shader, it is possible to load more data
      into a state buffer that can be set in individual global state values. The ability to map them into multiple
      shaders also simplifies state management, as updates to state values in a state buffer only need to be performed
      once in order to provide new values to all shaders where they are used.
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph>
      A very valuable use of state buffers is to store scene-wide common state values, such as the view and project
      matrices, the screen size in pixels, scene light positions and characteristics, and so on. By defining these state
      values in state buffers, the application can manage a single set of state values for these settings, and apply
      changes to these settings to all shaders in the program at once.
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph>
      A useful property of state buffers is the ability to define "pages", which are separate sets of values within the
      one state buffer. Each page of the state buffer shares the same layout, or in other words has the same number and
      type of fields in it, but each page can hold a distinct set of values for those fields. Separate pages of the
      state buffer can be bound at different times, even to the point of providing a unique state buffer page per
      renderable object if desired. Through the use of the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IStateBuffer.SetPageSettings">SetPageSettings</PageRef>
      method, it is also possible to allow the number of pages in the state buffer to be modified after creation, by
      calling the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IStateBuffer.ResizePageCount">ResizePageCount</PageRef> method. This is well
      suited to using paged state buffers to provide large sets of per-object state. The application can allocate page
      numbers to each renderable object, and update each page with the correct state values per object prior to drawing,
      with the number of pages growing or shrinking as required as the content of the scene changes.
    </Paragraph>
    <Note Type="Important">
      <Paragraph>
        Note that before a state buffer can be used, memory must be allocated for it by calling the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IStateBuffer.AllocateMemory">AllocateMemory</PageRef>
        method. This method cannot be called however until the layout for the state buffer has been defined. The
        recommended way to do this is by calling the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IStateBuffer.BindBufferLayout">BindBufferLayout</PageRef>
        method, which defines the names, types, and locations of the individual state fields within the buffer. For more
        information on how to create a state buffer layout, please refer to the documentation on the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IStateBufferLayout">IStateBufferLayout</PageRef>
        type. Alternatively, the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IStateBuffer.SetManualPageSize">SetManualPageSize</PageRef>
        method can be called, which allows an opaque buffer layout with a specific page size to be allocated. In this
        mode, state data can only be updated in a raw form using the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IStateBuffer.SetRawPageData">SetRawPageData</PageRef>
        method, but this may be more suitable if the renderer is used behind a higher level state management framework
        in a larger application.
      </Paragraph>
    </Note>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Enumerations">
    <TypeMemberList>
      <TypeMemberListEntry Name="PerformanceHint" TypeCategory="Enumeration" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IStateBuffer.PerformanceHint" Visibility="Public">
        Flags to provide hints to the graphics system about how the application will use this buffer. Correct use of
        performance hints allows the renderer to optimize the way the data is stored and modified to give the best
        performance.
      </TypeMemberListEntry>
    </TypeMemberList>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Members">
    <SubSection Title="Initialization methods">
      <FunctionMemberList>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="Delete" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IStateBuffer.Delete">
          Schedules the object for deletion. After calling this method, the object will be destroyed after the current
          frame completes drawing.
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="AllocateMemory" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IStateBuffer.AllocateMemory">
          Attempts to allocate memory for the buffer using the defined buffer layout and page settings
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
      </FunctionMemberList>
    </SubSection>
    <SubSection Title="Usage methods">
      <FunctionMemberList>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="SetPerformanceHints" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IStateBuffer.SetPerformanceHints">
          Provides hints to the renderer about how this object will be used. Correct use of hints is important to optimize performance.
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
      </FunctionMemberList>
    </SubSection>
    <SubSection Title="Format methods">
      <FunctionMemberList>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="SetManualPageSize" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IStateBuffer.SetManualPageSize">
          Defines a manual page size for the buffer. This can be used instead of calling <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IStateBuffer.BindBufferLayout">BindBufferLayout</PageRef>.
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="BindBufferLayout" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IStateBuffer.BindBufferLayout">
          Binds the specified state buffer layout to the state buffer. A layout must be defined using this method or <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IStateBuffer.SetManualPageSize">SetManualPageSize</PageRef>
          before calling <TypeRef>AllocateMemory</TypeRef>, and cannot be changed afterwards.
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="SetPageSettings" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IStateBuffer.SetPageSettings">
          Sets the page settings to use for the state buffer
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="ResizePageCount" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IStateBuffer.ResizePageCount">
          If the state buffer allows resizing, this allows the number of pages in the buffer to be changed.
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
      </FunctionMemberList>
    </SubSection>
    <SubSection Title="State value methods">
      <FunctionMemberList>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="GetStateValueId" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IStateBuffer.GetStateValueId">
          Retrieves an ID for the given state value
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="SetStateValue" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IStateBuffer.SetStateValue">
          Updates the target state variable in the first page of the buffer with the supplied value
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="SetStateValueForPage" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IStateBuffer.SetStateValueForPage">
          Updates the target state variable in the specified page of the buffer with the supplied value
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="SetRawPageData" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IStateBuffer.SetRawPageData">
          Writes the specified raw byte data directly into the state buffer at the specified location
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
      </FunctionMemberList>
    </SubSection>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="See also">
    <PageRefList>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.IStateBufferLayout">IStateBufferLayout</PageRefListEntry>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.IShaderProgram">IShaderProgram</PageRefListEntry>
    </PageRefList>
  </Section>
</XMLDocContent>
