<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<XMLDocContent PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderableNode.SetInstanceMode" Title="SetInstanceMode method" xmlns="http://www.cobaltrenderer.com/schema/XMLDocSchema.xsd">
  <Paragraph>
    <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.Welcome">Home</PageRef> ->
    <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderableNode">IRenderableNode</PageRef> ->
    SetInstanceMode
  </Paragraph>
  <Section Title="Description">
    <Paragraph>
      The <TypeRef>SetInstanceMode</TypeRef> method is used to configure instanced drawing. By default, an <TypeRef>IRenderableNode</TypeRef>
      will draw only once. Instanced drawing allows the object to be drawn more than once using a single underlying draw
      call. Through the use of the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderableNode.BindVertexInstanceAttribute">BindVertexInstanceAttribute</PageRef>
      method, additional data can be supplied which varies between each object instance, allowing each instance to be
      drawn in a different location or with different attributes such as size and colour. Data can also be retrieved
      from other data sources which varies per instance, by using the inbuilt instance number provided by the shader
      language as an index for array or texture lookups.
    </Paragraph>
  </Section>
  <Note Type="Important">
    <Paragraph>
      In order to set the <TypeRef>instanceOffset</TypeRef> parameter to a non-zero value, the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDevice.Feature">InstanceOffset feature</PageRef>
      must be supported on the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDevice">IGraphicsDevice</PageRef>, and
      activated when the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDevice.CreateRenderer">CreateRenderer</PageRef>
      method is called.
    </Paragraph>
  </Note>
  <Note Type="Important">
    <Paragraph>
      This method can be called at any time after the creation of the <TypeRef>IRenderableNode</TypeRef>, including when
      it has already been added to the render tree. Any changes made will not affect any current frame being drawn, and
      will take effect on the next frame.
    </Paragraph>
  </Note>
  <Section Title="Usage">
    <Code Language="C++"><![CDATA[SuccessToken SetInstanceMode(uint32_t instanceCount, uint32_t instanceOffset = 0);]]></Code>
    <SubSection Title="Argument list">
      <ArgumentList>
        <ArgumentListEntry Type="uint32_t" Name="instanceCount">
          Specifies the number of times to draw this renderable object
        </ArgumentListEntry>
        <ArgumentListEntry Type="uint32_t" Name="instanceOffset">
          Specifies a numeric offset to apply to the instance number passed to the shader program. Without an offset,
          the instance number will begin at 0 for the first instance drawn.
        </ArgumentListEntry>
      </ArgumentList>
    </SubSection>
    <SubSection Title="Return value">
      <ReturnValue Type="SuccessToken!cobalt.graphics.SuccessToken">
        True if the instance count and offset values were successfully updated, false otherwise. There are currently no
        circumstances under which this method will fail, however in future updates the supplied values may be validated
        in debug builds to ensure they meet constraints around instancing on the target device. An assertion will be
        raised in debug builds if the result isn't tested.
      </ReturnValue>
    </SubSection>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="See also">
    <PageRefList>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderableNode">IRenderableNode</PageRefListEntry>
    </PageRefList>
  </Section>
</XMLDocContent>
