<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<XMLDocContent PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderableNode.SetPrimitiveMode" Title="SetPrimitiveMode method" xmlns="http://www.cobaltrenderer.com/schema/XMLDocSchema.xsd">
  <Paragraph>
    <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.Welcome">Home</PageRef> ->
    <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderableNode">IRenderableNode</PageRef> ->
    SetPrimitiveMode
  </Paragraph>
  <Section Title="Description">
    <Paragraph>
      The <TypeRef>SetPrimitiveMode</TypeRef> method specifies how vertex data is interpreted to form geometric
      primitives. The <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderableNode.PrimitiveMode">PrimitiveMode</PageRef>
      enumeration specifies the valid list of primitive modes.
    </Paragraph>
  </Section>
  <Note Type="Important">
    <Paragraph>
      There is no default value for the primitive mode, and it must be set before this node is added to the tree.
      Attempts to add an <TypeRef>IRenderableNode</TypeRef> as a child to an <TypeRef>IStateGroupNode</TypeRef>
      without the primitive mode being set will be ignored, and an error will be logged.
    </Paragraph>
  </Note>
  <Note Type="Warning">
    <Paragraph>
      Once the <TypeRef>IRenderableNode</TypeRef> has been added as a child node, the primitive mode can no longer be
      changed, and calling the <TypeRef>SetPrimitiveMode</TypeRef> will return false. Removing the node as a child later
      will also not allow the primitive mode to be modified. If you want to change the primitive mode for a renderable
      which has been added as a child, you need to create a new <TypeRef>IRenderableNode</TypeRef> object.
    </Paragraph>
  </Note>
  <Note Type="Warning">
    <Paragraph>
      Due to API limitations, primitive restart is always enabled under Direct3D 11 renderers, and cannot be turned off.
      To avoid issues, you should consider the primitive restart index values to be reserved, and avoid their use
      regardless of whether primitive restart is enabled or not.
    </Paragraph>
  </Note>
  <Section Title="Usage">
    <Code Language="C++"><![CDATA[SuccessToken SetPrimitiveMode(PrimitiveMode primitiveMode, bool primitiveRestartEnabled = false);]]></Code>
    <SubSection Title="Argument list">
      <ArgumentList>
        <ArgumentListEntry Type="PrimitiveMode!cobalt.graphics.IRenderableNode.PrimitiveMode" Name="primitiveMode">
          The <TypeRef>PrimitiveMode</TypeRef> to use when drawing this object
        </ArgumentListEntry>
        <ArgumentListEntry Type="bool" Name="primitiveRestartEnabled">
          For <TypeRef>LineStrip</TypeRef> and <TypeRef>TriangleStrip</TypeRef> primitive modes, specifies whether
          primitive restart is enabled.
        </ArgumentListEntry>
      </ArgumentList>
    </SubSection>
    <SubSection Title="Return value">
      <ReturnValue Type="SuccessToken!cobalt.graphics.SuccessToken">
        True if the primitive mode was successfully modified, false otherwise. This method will only fail if the
        renderable node has already been added as a child node. An assertion will be raised in debug builds if the
        result isn't tested.
      </ReturnValue>
    </SubSection>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="See also">
    <PageRefList>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderableNode">IRenderableNode</PageRefListEntry>
    </PageRefList>
  </Section>
</XMLDocContent>
