<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<XMLDocContent PageName="cobalt.marshalling.IMarshalSource" Title="IMarshalSource" xmlns="http://www.cobaltrenderer.com/schema/XMLDocSchema.xsd">
  <Section Title="Overview">
    <Paragraph>
      The <TypeRef>IMarshalSource</TypeRef> family provides the low-level source-side interface used by the marshalling library to extract data from a bound
      object and flatten it into a representation that can cross the assembly boundary. The concrete helper class <PageRef PageName="cobalt.marshalling.MarshalSource">MarshalSource</PageRef>
      derives from these interfaces and is what the public marshal helpers normally create internally.
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph>
      The exact set of members present on this type varies significantly between specializations. In general, the specializations cover the same families of
      operations as the higher level <TypeRef>Marshal::In</TypeRef> and <TypeRef>Marshal::Ret</TypeRef> wrappers: whole-object marshalling, marshal
      without move where applicable, and container-specific access for STL types such as <TypeRef>std::vector</TypeRef>, <TypeRef>std::array</TypeRef>,
      <TypeRef>std::basic_string</TypeRef>, <TypeRef>std::pair</TypeRef>, and <TypeRef>std::tuple</TypeRef>.
    </Paragraph>
  </Section>

  <Section Title="Member Families">
    <SubSection Title="Marshalling methods">
      <Paragraph>
        Source specializations provide methods that return a marshalled copy of the bound object, and where supported, a variant that preserves the source
        object instead of moving from it.
      </Paragraph>
    </SubSection>
    <SubSection Title="Container metadata">
      <Paragraph>
        STL container specializations provide size, capacity, and empty queries where those operations make sense for the bound type.
      </Paragraph>
    </SubSection>
    <SubSection Title="Element retrieval">
      <Paragraph>
        Specializations for indexed or composite types expose element-specific retrieval functions so that the target side can reconstruct the original
        object layout safely.
      </Paragraph>
    </SubSection>
  </Section>

  <Section Title="Usage">
    <Paragraph>
      Application code normally does not create <TypeRef>IMarshalSource</TypeRef> objects directly. The class exists to support the internals of the higher
      level marshal helpers, and the public source wrapper <PageRef PageName="cobalt.marshalling.MarshalSource">MarshalSource</PageRef> should be preferred
      whenever direct use is required.
    </Paragraph>
  </Section>

  <Section Title="See also">
    <PageRefList>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.marshalling.MarshalSource">MarshalSource</PageRefListEntry>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.marshalling.MarshalIn">Marshal::In</PageRefListEntry>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.marshalling.MarshalRet">Marshal::Ret</PageRefListEntry>
    </PageRefList>
  </Section>
</XMLDocContent>
