<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<XMLDocContent PageName="cobalt.graphics.ITransferBatch" Title="ITransferBatch interface" xmlns="http://www.cobaltrenderer.com/schema/XMLDocSchema.xsd">
  <Paragraph>
    <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.Welcome">Home</PageRef> ->
    ITransferBatch
  </Paragraph>
  <Section Title="Declaration">
    <Code Language="C++"><![CDATA[class ITransferBatch;]]></Code>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Description">
    <Paragraph>
      By default, all calls to <TypeRef>QueueDataUpdate</TypeRef> and <TypeRef>QueueDataTransfer</TypeRef> methods are
      scheduled for processing after the current frame completes drawing, and before draw operations for the next frame
      begin. This allows for data changes to be scheduled which are guaranteed to be fully applied before the next
      frame, without interfering with the current frame being drawn. The <TypeRef>ITransferBatch</TypeRef> interface
      allows these operations to be scheduled differently, potentially starting immediately when the batch is submitted
      in parallel with the current frame being drawn, or being allowed to continue to execute past the start of the next
      frame. The application also has the ability to synchronize with the batch, being able to inspect completion state,
      or suspend the calling thread until all transfers in the batch are complete.
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph>
      You should only use transfer batches when you have a case that can benefit from them. There are two main scenarios
      where this is likely to be the case. One is where you have highly dynamic content that changes each frame. In this
      case, you may want to keep two separate sets of buffers, one for displaying in the current frame, and one for
      updating for use in the next frame, and switch the buffers each frame. By using transfer batches, the renderer may
      be able to perform the data updates "for free" during the drawing of the current frame. The second scenario where
      transfer batches may be useful is if you need to perform pontentially very large and long running transfers. In
      this case, the use of a transfer batch may allow the application to begin the transfer without holding up the
      start of subsequent frames.
    </Paragraph>
    <Note Type="Important">
      <Paragraph>
        It is not guaranteed for transfer batches to have any impact on the timing of transfers whatsoever. Unless the
        underlying graphics API supports multiple command queues, it is not possible to implement this feature. OpenGL
        renderers, and Direct3D renderers prior to Direct3D 12 are unable to improve performance using transfer batches.
      </Paragraph>
    </Note>
    <Note Type="Warning">
      <Paragraph>
        When using transfer batches, it is the responsibility of the application to ensure that any buffers being
        accessed are not in use for any other operations, including drawing, from the time the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.ITransferBatch.SubmitBatch">SubmitBatch</PageRef>
        method is called until the transfer is complete. This includes a previously submitted frame that has not
        completed drawing yet.
      </Paragraph>
    </Note>
    <Note Type="Warning">
      <Paragraph>
        When setting a transfer batch to start immediately, all existing buffer contents are invalidated and become
        undefined. This means you cannot do partial updates to an existing buffer if you schedule a transfer batch to
        start immediately. If you require partial buffer updates, you must set the transfer to start after the end of
        the current frame, or the results are undefined.
      </Paragraph>
    </Note>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Enumerations">
    <TypeMemberList>
      <TypeMemberListEntry Name="StartTiming" TypeCategory="Enumeration" PageName="cobalt.graphics.ITransferBatch.StartTiming" Visibility="Public">
        The start timing for a transfer batch, set when the batch is created through the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderer.CreateTransferBatch">CreateTransferBatch</PageRef> method.
      </TypeMemberListEntry>
      <TypeMemberListEntry Name="EndTiming" TypeCategory="Enumeration" PageName="cobalt.graphics.ITransferBatch.EndTiming" Visibility="Public">
        The end timing for a transfer batch, set when the batch is created through the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderer.CreateTransferBatch">CreateTransferBatch</PageRef> method.
      </TypeMemberListEntry>
    </TypeMemberList>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Members">
    <SubSection Title="Initialization methods">
      <FunctionMemberList>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="Delete" PageName="cobalt.graphics.ITransferBatch.Delete">
          Schedules the object for deletion. After calling this method, the object will be destroyed after the current
          frame completes drawing.
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
      </FunctionMemberList>
    </SubSection>
    <SubSection Title="Submission methods">
      <FunctionMemberList>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="SubmitBatch" PageName="cobalt.graphics.ITransferBatch.SubmitBatch">
          Submits the contents of this batch to the renderer for processing. Note that processing does not necessarily
          begin immediately. The <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.ITransferBatch.StartTiming">StartTiming</PageRef>
          entry that was specified for the batch when it was created with the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderer.CreateTransferBatch">CreateTransferBatch</PageRef>
          method controls when the batch begins execution.
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="IsSubmitted" PageName="cobalt.graphics.ITransferBatch.IsSubmitted">
          Returns true if the batch has been submitted for processing
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="IsComplete" PageName="cobalt.graphics.ITransferBatch.IsComplete">
          Returns true if the batch has completed processing
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="WaitForComplete" PageName="cobalt.graphics.ITransferBatch.WaitForComplete">
          Blocks execution of the calling thread until the batch has completed processing
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
      </FunctionMemberList>
    </SubSection>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="See also">
    <PageRefList>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.IIndexBuffer">IIndexBuffer</PageRefListEntry>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.IVertexBuffer">IVertexBuffer</PageRefListEntry>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.IndexAttribute">IndexAttribute</PageRefListEntry>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.VertexAttribute">VertexAttribute</PageRefListEntry>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.ITextureBuffer">ITextureBuffer</PageRefListEntry>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.IDataArray">IDataArray</PageRefListEntry>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.ITexelArray">ITexelArray</PageRefListEntry>
    </PageRefList>
  </Section>
</XMLDocContent>
