<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<XMLDocContent PageName="cobalt.graphics.IStateBufferLayout" Title="IStateBufferLayout interface" xmlns="http://www.cobaltrenderer.com/schema/XMLDocSchema.xsd">
  <Paragraph>
    <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.Welcome">Home</PageRef> ->
    IStateBufferLayout
  </Paragraph>
  <Section Title="Declaration">
    <Code Language="C++"><![CDATA[class IStateBufferLayout;]]></Code>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Description">
    <Paragraph>
      The <TypeRef>IStateBufferLayout</TypeRef> interface defines the layout of a state buffer for use in a shader
      program. As state buffers generally contain multiple fields, which are mapped into the shader program as a large
      block of data, it is necessary to know the sizes and locations of the individual fields within the buffer, and
      their associated names, in order to allow these fields to be individually written to through the
      <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IStateBuffer.SetStateValue">SetStateValue</PageRef> method of the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IStateBuffer">IStateBuffer</PageRef>
      class.
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph>
      There are two ways to initialize an <TypeRef>IStateBufferLayout</TypeRef> object. The preferred way is to build
      the state buffer layout from the shader program itself. After creating an <TypeRef>IStateBufferLayout</TypeRef>
      object, it can be passed directly into the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IShaderProgram.LoadStateBufferLayoutFromShader">LoadStateBufferLayoutFromShader</PageRef>
      method on an <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IShaderProgram">IShaderProgram</PageRef> object. This uses shader
      reflection to determine the full layout of the state buffer from the structure that is defined in the shader
      itself. This is the best approach, as it is simple for the application to do, and it allows the shader programs
      and the renderer maximum flexibility in how the state buffer is laid out. The alternate approach is for the
      application to define the contents of the state buffer manually, using the state layout building methods listed
      below. Fields must be added in the order they are defined, with each field being appended using the standard
      buffer layout rules for the renderer that was loaded. For Direct3D renderers, this uses the formally defined
      <URL DisplayName="Packing Rules for Constant Variables">https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/desktop/direct3dhlsl/dx-graphics-hlsl-packing-rules</URL>.
      For OpenGL, the "std140" layout rules are used, as found in <URL DisplayName="Section 7.6.2.2">https://www.khronos.org/registry/OpenGL/specs/gl/glspec45.core.pdf#page=159</URL>
      of the OpenGL 4.5 Specification.
    </Paragraph>
    <Note Type="Warning">
      <Paragraph>
        Please note if you are using GLSL as your shader language and defining your own manually built layouts, there is
        a specific warning not to use <TypeRef>vec3</TypeRef> types. See following note from the <URL DisplayName="official OpenGL wiki">https://www.khronos.org/opengl/wiki/Interface_Block_(GLSL)</URL>:
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph>
        "Implementations sometimes get the std140 layout wrong for vec3 components. You are advised to manually pad your
        structures/arrays out and avoid using vec3 at all."
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph>
        Although specific vendors and driver versions are not named, this advice should be followed when using the GLSL
        shader language and manually built state buffer layouts, to avoid compatibility problems.
      </Paragraph>
    </Note>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Enumerations">
    <TypeMemberList>
      <TypeMemberListEntry Name="DataType" TypeCategory="Enumeration" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IStateBufferLayout.DataType" Visibility="Public">
        Identifies the scalar type of fields, vectors, and matrices appended during manual state buffer layout construction.
      </TypeMemberListEntry>
    </TypeMemberList>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Members">
    <SubSection Title="Initialization methods">
      <FunctionMemberList>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="Delete" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IStateBufferLayout.Delete">
          Schedules the object for deletion. After calling this method, the object will be destroyed after the current
          frame completes drawing.
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
      </FunctionMemberList>
    </SubSection>
    <SubSection Title="State layout building methods">
      <FunctionMemberList>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="BeginLayoutDefinition" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IStateBufferLayout.BeginLayoutDefinition">
          Starts the process of constructing a state buffer layout
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="AppendField" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IStateBufferLayout.AppendField">
          Appends a scalar field to the state buffer layout
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="AppendVector" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IStateBufferLayout.AppendVector">
          Appends a vector field to the state buffer layout
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="AppendMatrix" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IStateBufferLayout.AppendMatrix">
          Appends a matrix field to the state buffer layout
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="ConstructStateLayout" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IStateBufferLayout.ConstructStateLayout">
          Completes the process of constructing a state buffer layout
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
      </FunctionMemberList>
    </SubSection>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="See also">
    <PageRefList>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.IStateBuffer">IStateBuffer</PageRefListEntry>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.IShaderProgram">IShaderProgram</PageRefListEntry>
    </PageRefList>
  </Section>
</XMLDocContent>
