<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<XMLDocContent PageName="cobalt.graphics.ReadWriteMutex" Title="ReadWriteMutex helper" xmlns="http://www.cobaltrenderer.com/schema/XMLDocSchema.xsd">
  <Paragraph>
    <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.Welcome">Home</PageRef> ->
    ReadWriteMutex
  </Paragraph>
  <Section Title="Declaration">
    <Code Language="C++"><![CDATA[class ReadWriteMutex;]]></Code>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Description">
    <Paragraph>
      The <TypeRef>ReadWriteMutex</TypeRef> type is a helper type only, and does not feature on the renderer interface
      itself. This is an optional type which is available for use by the calling application to assist with threading.
      As detailed in the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.Concepts.ThreadingModel">Threading Model</PageRef> section, the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderer.StartNewFrame">StartNewFrame</PageRef>
      method on the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderer">IRenderer</PageRef> interface must be called in
      complete exclusion to all others, on all objects. This allows types on the renderer to operate largely lock free,
      and be as lightweight as possible. The tradeoff is this one synchronisation requirement is pushed back on the
      application. If the application due to design never has a chance of overlapping a call to <TypeRef>StartNewFrame</TypeRef>
      with other API calls on another thread, no further synchronisation is required. If this is possible however, the
      <TypeRef>ReadWriteMutex</TypeRef> is provided to assist with this case.
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph>
      This class implements a "many concurrent readers, one exclusive writer" lock pattern, which allows a writer to
      "starve out" read requests until it obtains the lock. This allows the application to satisfy the synchronisation
      requirements by obtaining read locks before each block of API calls, and a write lock before calling <TypeRef>StartNewFrame</TypeRef>.
      This gives low overhead, while allowing multiple threads to access the API in parallel on separate threads,
      without allowing thread starvation on the thread that calls <TypeRef>StartNewFrame</TypeRef>. Read locks are also
      re-entrant on the same thread for simplicity.
    </Paragraph>
    <Note Type="Warning">
      <Paragraph>
        Read locks are re-entrant, however that is only guaranteed to work if each read lock on a given thread is
        released in the reverse order they are taken.
      </Paragraph>
    </Note>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Members">
    <SubSection Title="Nested types">
      <TypeMemberList>
        <TypeMemberListEntry Name="ReadLock" TypeCategory="Class" Visibility="Public">
          A scoped <TypeRef>ReadLock</TypeRef> type, which releases the lock when the object is destroyed.
        </TypeMemberListEntry>
        <TypeMemberListEntry Name="WriteLock" TypeCategory="Class" Visibility="Public">
          A scoped <TypeRef>WriteLock</TypeRef> type, which releases the lock when the object is destroyed.
        </TypeMemberListEntry>
      </TypeMemberList>
    </SubSection>
    <SubSection Title="Lock methods">
      <FunctionMemberList>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="ObtainReadLock" PageName="cobalt.graphics.ReadWriteMutex.ObtainReadLock">
          Obtains a read lock for this mutex. This method blocks the calling thread until the lock can be obtained.
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="ObtainWriteLock" PageName="cobalt.graphics.ReadWriteMutex.ObtainWriteLock">
          Obtains a write lock for this mutex. This method blocks the calling thread until the lock can be obtained.
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="ReadLock.Unlock" PageName="cobalt.graphics.ReadWriteMutex.ReadLock.Unlock">
          Releases the read lock manually. This allows a lock to be released early, however the lock will also be released when the lock object is destroyed.
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="WriteLock.Unlock" PageName="cobalt.graphics.ReadWriteMutex.WriteLock.Unlock">
          Releases the write lock manually. This allows a lock to be released early, however the lock will also be released when the lock object is destroyed.
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
      </FunctionMemberList>
    </SubSection>
  </Section>
</XMLDocContent>
