<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<XMLDocContent PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDeviceEnumerator.Delete" Title="Delete method" xmlns="http://www.cobaltrenderer.com/schema/XMLDocSchema.xsd">
  <Paragraph>
    <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.Welcome">Home</PageRef> ->
    <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDeviceEnumerator">IGraphicsDeviceEnumerator</PageRef> ->
    Delete
  </Paragraph>
  <Section Title="Description">
    <Paragraph>
      The <TypeRef>Delete</TypeRef> method destroys the object. Note that unlike all created objects from the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderer">IRenderer</PageRef>
      interface, deleting the renderer does not perform deferred destruction, and fully destroys the object before it
      returns. Also note that <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDevice">IGraphicsDevice</PageRef> objects
      returned through this interface are owned by the enumerator, and are destroyed when the enumerator is destroyed.
    </Paragraph>
    <Note Type="Important">
      <Paragraph>
        While you must keep the <TypeRef>IGraphicsDeviceEnumerator</TypeRef> around in order to be able to retain access
        to the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDevice">IGraphicsDevice</PageRef> objects returned through
        it, deleting the <TypeRef>IGraphicsDeviceEnumerator</TypeRef> and its owned <TypeRef>IGraphicsDevice</TypeRef>
        objects has no impact on <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderer">IRenderer</PageRef> objects which have
        been created. It is perfectly valid to keep an <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderer">IRenderer</PageRef>
        object alive after the device it was created from has been destroyed.
      </Paragraph>
    </Note>
    <Note Type="Warning">
      <Paragraph>
        Under normal circumstances, this method should never need to be called directly. The <TypeRef>unique_ptr</TypeRef>
        which is returned when this object is constructed will call this method itself when the pointer is released. You
        must not call this method if the object lifetime is still being managed by the <TypeRef>unique_ptr</TypeRef>
        object, otherwise the method will be called more than once. If this occurs the behaviour is undefined, and it may
        result in runtime errors.
      </Paragraph>
    </Note>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Usage">
    <Code Language="C++"><![CDATA[void Delete();]]></Code>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="See also">
    <PageRefList>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDeviceEnumerator">IGraphicsDeviceEnumerator</PageRefListEntry>
    </PageRefList>
  </Section>
</XMLDocContent>
