<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<XMLDocContent PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDeviceEnumerator.EnumerateDevices" Title="EnumerateDevices method" xmlns="http://www.cobaltrenderer.com/schema/XMLDocSchema.xsd">
  <Paragraph>
    <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.Welcome">Home</PageRef> ->
    <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDeviceEnumerator">IGraphicsDeviceEnumerator</PageRef> ->
    EnumerateDevices
  </Paragraph>
  <Section Title="Description">
    <Paragraph>
      The <TypeRef>EnumerateDevices</TypeRef> method scans for available graphics devices on the system, which implement
      the required version of the underlying rendering API used by this renderer plugin. Although information on located
      devices is not returned directly by this method, after successfully completing, the available devices can be
      enumerated by calling other methods on the <TypeRef>IGraphicsDeviceEnumerator</TypeRef> object, such as
      <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDeviceEnumerator.GetAllDevices">GetAllDevices</PageRef> and
      <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDeviceEnumerator.GetPreferredDevice">GetPreferredDevice</PageRef>.
    </Paragraph>
    <Note Type="Important">
      <Paragraph>
        A successful call to this method means that the enumeration operation completed, not that at least one compatible
        device was found. It is valid for this method to return true while
        <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDeviceEnumerator.GetAllDevices">GetAllDevices</PageRef> returns an
        empty list, for example on a system without a compatible graphics driver, without the requested renderer API, or
        without a device compatible with the supplied <TypeRef>EnumerationFlags</TypeRef>. Applications should explicitly
        check <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDeviceEnumerator.FoundDevice">FoundDevice</PageRef> or the
        returned device list before attempting to select or create a renderer from a device.
      </Paragraph>
    </Note>
    <Note Type="Warning">
      <Paragraph>
        Calling this method destroys any previously allocated <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDevice">IGraphicsDevice</PageRef>
        objects returned by this object, even if the same devices are located again during the enumeration process.
        Generally this method should only ever need to be called once, but this method is called after a previous
        successful call, it is the responsibility of the calling application to ensure any previously returned
        <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDevice">IGraphicsDevice</PageRef> references are not retained or
        accessed after this method is called.
      </Paragraph>
    </Note>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Usage">
    <Code Language="C++"><![CDATA[SuccessToken EnumerateDevices(EnumerationFlags flags = EnumerationFlags::None);]]></Code>
    <SubSection Title="Argument list">
      <ArgumentList>
        <ArgumentListEntry Type="DeviceType!cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDeviceEnumerator.EnumerationFlags" Name="flags">
          Optional flags to control the enumeration process
        </ArgumentListEntry>
      </ArgumentList>
    </SubSection>
    <SubSection Title="Return value">
      <ReturnValue Type="SuccessToken!cobalt.graphics.SuccessToken">
        True if the enumeration process completed, false if enumeration itself failed. A true result does not guarantee
        that any compatible devices were found.
      </ReturnValue>
    </SubSection>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="See also">
    <PageRefList>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDeviceEnumerator">IGraphicsDeviceEnumerator</PageRefListEntry>
    </PageRefList>
  </Section>
</XMLDocContent>
