<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<XMLDocContent PageName="cobalt.graphics.IProgramNode.Delete" Title="Delete method" xmlns="http://www.cobaltrenderer.com/schema/XMLDocSchema.xsd">
  <Paragraph>
    <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.Welcome">Home</PageRef> ->
    <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IProgramNode">IProgramNode</PageRef> ->
    Delete
  </Paragraph>
  <Section Title="Description">
    <Paragraph>
      The <TypeRef>Delete</TypeRef> method schedules this object for deletion. The <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderer">IRenderer</PageRef>
      object which created this object performs deferred destruction, and will prevent the object being destroyed until
      any current drawing process completes. This relieves the application from the burden of tracking which resources
      are still in use, and determining when they can be safely destroyed.
    </Paragraph>
    <Note Type="Warning">
      <Paragraph>
        The renderer does not perform any checks to ensure that an object is not still attached to the render tree when
        it is scheduled for deletion. It is the responsibility of the application to ensure that all resources which are
        being deleted will not attempt to be used by subsequent frames.
      </Paragraph>
    </Note>
    <Note Type="Warning">
      <Paragraph>
        Under normal circumstances, this method should never need to be called directly. The <TypeRef>unique_ptr</TypeRef>
        which is returned when this object is constructed will call this method itself when the pointer is released. You
        must not call this method if the object lifetime is still being managed by the <TypeRef>unique_ptr</TypeRef>
        object, otherwise the method will be called more than once. If this occurs the behaviour is undefined, and it
        may result in runtime errors.
      </Paragraph>
    </Note>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Usage">
    <Code Language="C++"><![CDATA[void Delete();]]></Code>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="See also">
    <PageRefList>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.IProgramNode">IProgramNode</PageRefListEntry>
    </PageRefList>
  </Section>
</XMLDocContent>
