<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<XMLDocContent PageName="cobalt.graphics.IProgramNode.BindShaderProgram" Title="BindShaderProgram method" xmlns="http://www.cobaltrenderer.com/schema/XMLDocSchema.xsd">
  <Paragraph>
    <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.Welcome">Home</PageRef> ->
    <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IProgramNode">IProgramNode</PageRef> ->
    BindShaderProgram
  </Paragraph>
  <Section Title="Description">
    <Paragraph>
      The <TypeRef>BindShaderProgram</TypeRef> method specifies the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IShaderProgram">IShaderProgram</PageRef>
      object to use as the shader program for all renderable content under this node. All binding commands or state
      values which are set under this node must refer to IDs returned by the shader program specified here.
    </Paragraph>
    <Note Type="Important">
      <Paragraph>
        Changing the bound shader program used for rendering is an expensive operation, which is why this information is
        set at a high level in the render tree. Applications should aim for the absolute minimum number of changes to
        the shader program, so you should attempt to group all your content which shares the same shader program under
        the one render pass in the same <TypeRef>IProgramNode</TypeRef> node, and rely on child <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IStateGroupNode">IStateGroupNode</PageRef>
        objects to divide content further if needed.
      </Paragraph>
    </Note>
    <Note Type="Important">
      <Paragraph>
        It is strongly recommended to minimize the number of separate shaders your application uses. Shader programs can
        be very large and involve many conditional tests, and still be much more efficient than using sets of separate
        smaller shaders and having to change programs multiple times during the rendering process. For this reason, your
        application should aim to use large shader programs which provide state values to enable different kinds of
        operations as needed, such as texturing, stippling, lighting, or shading effects.
      </Paragraph>
    </Note>
    <Note Type="Warning">
      <Paragraph>
        The associated <TypeRef>IShaderProgram</TypeRef> for a program node can only be set once. Since all bindings and
        state changes associated with a program depend on the particular program that has been bound, changing the
        program would necessitate changing all the content which has been added to it in some way. If a new program is
        required, a new node must be constructed to use it.
      </Paragraph>
    </Note>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Usage">
    <Code Language="C++"><![CDATA[SuccessToken BindShaderProgram(IShaderProgram* program);]]></Code>
    <SubSection Title="Argument list">
      <ArgumentList>
        <ArgumentListEntry Type="IShaderProgram*!cobalt.graphics.IShaderProgram" Name="program">
          The <TypeRef>IShaderProgram</TypeRef> to use for content under this node
        </ArgumentListEntry>
      </ArgumentList>
    </SubSection>
    <SubSection Title="Return value">
      <ReturnValue Type="SuccessToken!cobalt.graphics.SuccessToken">
        True if the enumeration process was successful, false otherwise. An assertion will be raised in debug builds if
        the result isn't tested.
      </ReturnValue>
    </SubSection>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="See also">
    <PageRefList>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.IProgramNode">IProgramNode</PageRefListEntry>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.IShaderProgram">IShaderProgram</PageRefListEntry>
    </PageRefList>
  </Section>
</XMLDocContent>
