<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<XMLDocContent PageName="cobalt.graphics.Concepts.AllocationModel" Title="Allocation Model" xmlns="http://www.cobaltrenderer.com/schema/XMLDocSchema.xsd">
  <Paragraph>
    <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.Welcome">Home</PageRef> ->
    Allocation Model
  </Paragraph>
  <Section Title="Renderer Allocation">
    <Paragraph>
      A Cobalt Renderer application normally starts by selecting a renderer plugin with
      <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.RenderPluginEnumerator">RenderPluginEnumerator</PageRef>. The selected
      <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.RendererPlugin">RendererPlugin</PageRef> creates an
      <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDeviceEnumerator">IGraphicsDeviceEnumerator</PageRef>, the enumerator
      selects an <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDevice">IGraphicsDevice</PageRef>, and the device creates
      the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderer">IRenderer</PageRef> through
      <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDevice.CreateRenderer">CreateRenderer</PageRef>.
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph>
      The lower-level <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.GetCobaltAPIVersion">GetCobaltAPIVersion</PageRef> and
      <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.GetRendererPlugin">GetRendererPlugin</PageRef> exports still exist for applications
      that manage plugin loading themselves, but the plugin enumerator is the preferred high-level entry point. It
      handles platform-specific dynamic library loading, checks Cobalt Renderer API compatibility before retrieving
      renderer plugin records, and keeps the plugin selection code independent from the renderer implementation names.
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph>
      <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.RendererPlugin.CreateGraphicsDeviceEnumerator">CreateGraphicsDeviceEnumerator</PageRef>
      returns an <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDeviceEnumerator">IGraphicsDeviceEnumerator</PageRef>.
      Keep the <TypeRef>RendererPlugin</TypeRef> object alive for as long as the enumerator, devices, or renderers created from the plugin are still in
      use. The plugin object keeps the dynamic library loaded while objects implemented by that library exist.
    </Paragraph>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Renderer-Owned Objects">
    <Paragraph>
      Most renderer objects are created from the <TypeRef>IRenderer</TypeRef> interface and returned through
      <TypeRef>unique_ptr</TypeRef> aliases with renderer-specific deleters. Destroying the smart pointer calls the
      corresponding <TypeRef>Delete</TypeRef> method and removes the object from application ownership.
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph>
      The renderer uses deferred deletion internally. It is safe to release objects that are still referenced by a frame
      currently being drawn, because the native graphics resources are retained until the renderer knows they are no
      longer needed. If the application must know that deferred destruction has completed, call
      <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderer.WaitForDeferredDeletionComplete">WaitForDeferredDeletionComplete</PageRef>.
    </Paragraph>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Resource Allocation">
    <Paragraph>
      Buffer and texture resources are usually configured before memory is allocated. For example, a vertex buffer binds
      its attributes before <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IVertexBuffer.AllocateMemory">AllocateMemory</PageRef>
      is called, and a texture buffer has its dimensions, format, sample count, and mipmap settings defined before its
      memory is allocated. Initial data should also be provided before allocation when the resource is created with
      static contents.
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph>
      After allocation, the shape of a resource is intentionally more restricted. Existing contents can be updated
      through the resource update APIs or <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.ITransferBatch">ITransferBatch</PageRef>,
      but structural details such as bound attributes, texture dimensions, and allocation formats should be treated as
      immutable. This keeps the renderer's native resource ownership clear and avoids hidden reallocations in the middle
      of frame building.
    </Paragraph>
  </Section>
  <Paragraph>
    Next page, <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.Concepts.Shaders">Shaders</PageRef>
  </Paragraph>
</XMLDocContent>
