<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<XMLDocContent PageName="cobalt.graphics.Concepts.BestPractices" Title="Best Practices" xmlns="http://www.cobaltrenderer.com/schema/XMLDocSchema.xsd">
  <Paragraph>
    <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.Welcome">Home</PageRef> ->
    Best Practices
  </Paragraph>
  <Section Title="Render Tree Node Usage">
    <Paragraph>
      The render tree should be organised around rendering state, not around the logical ownership structure used by the
      application. Group renderables by render pass, shader program, and compatible state so that the renderer can draw
      many objects without repeatedly changing native pipelines.
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph>
      Shader program changes are usually among the more expensive transitions. Prefer a smaller number of general-purpose
      shader programs with state values, state buffers, textures, and compile-time constant state values controlling
      behaviour, rather than many nearly identical shader programs. This should still be balanced against shader
      complexity. A single shader with excessive branching or unused work can be slower than a small set of well-chosen
      programs.
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph>
      State group nodes are useful for sharing fixed-function state and resource bindings across many renderables. If a
      set of renderables uses the same depth, blend, culling, textures, or state buffers, set that state once on a
      common group node where possible. This reduces repeated binding work and keeps material or pass state easier to
      reason about.
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph>
      Renderable nodes do not usually require new pipelines by themselves, but each renderable still represents draw
      work. Batch geometry when practical, use index buffers to share vertices, and consider indirect drawing for large
      numbers of similar small draw operations. Modern graphics hardware is generally more efficient when it receives
      fewer, larger submissions than many tiny submissions.
    </Paragraph>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="State Values and Bindings">
    <Paragraph>
      Resolve shader resource names once during setup and keep the returned IDs. Re-resolving names from strings inside
      a render loop is unnecessary work and can hide errors until later than needed. Material, pass, or shader setup
      data is usually the right place to cache IDs for state values, vertex attributes, textures, samplers, data arrays,
      and texel arrays.
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph>
      Prefer setting shared state values and bindings on default state objects or state group nodes, and use renderable
      bindings only for values that genuinely vary per renderable. When many values are updated together, a state buffer
      is often a better fit than many individual state values.
    </Paragraph>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Resource Updates">
    <Paragraph>
      Avoid reallocating resources as part of normal frame updates. Create buffers and textures with the layout,
      dimensions, usage flags, and performance hints that match the intended use, then update their contents through
      queue methods or transfer batches. Reallocation can force native resource destruction, new allocation, and
      synchronization with in-flight work.
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph>
      Use initial data when creating static resources. For dynamic resources, prefer predictable update patterns and
      consider rotating between multiple buffers when the CPU and GPU may need different versions of the same logical
      data at the same time.
    </Paragraph>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Frame Flow">
    <Paragraph>
      Keep <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderer.StartNewFrame">StartNewFrame</PageRef> as a clear frame
      boundary. Other threads may prepare renderer objects concurrently, but frame submission itself must be exclusive
      with all other calls on the renderer and objects created by it. A read/write lock pattern is often a good match:
      update work takes shared locks, and frame submission takes the exclusive lock.
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph>
      Avoid waiting for draw completion or output capture unless the application really needs the result. Letting the
      renderer continue asynchronously gives the application more opportunity to prepare later frames while the current
      frame is drawing.
    </Paragraph>
  </Section>
</XMLDocContent>
