<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<XMLDocContent PageName="cobalt.graphics.Concepts.RenderTree" Title="The Render Tree" xmlns="http://www.cobaltrenderer.com/schema/XMLDocSchema.xsd">
  <Paragraph>
    <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.Welcome">Home</PageRef> ->
    Render Tree
  </Paragraph>
  <Section Title="The Render Tree">
    <Paragraph>
      The render tree is the structure Cobalt Renderer uses to describe the work required to render a frame. It is not
      intended to replace an application's own scene graph. Instead, it groups rendering work by the expensive state
      changes that graphics APIs care about: render pass outputs, shader programs, fixed-function state, resource
      bindings, and draw inputs. Keeping these groups explicit lets the renderer create and reuse efficient native
      pipelines while avoiding unnecessary transitions between them.
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph>
      The tree has four levels. A render pass node describes where work is rendered. A program node describes the shader
      program. A state group node describes fixed-function state and inherited shader resources. A renderable node
      describes the geometry or indirect draw that is submitted. The diagram below illustrates the four levels and the
      resources associated with each level.
    </Paragraph>
    <Image>RenderTree</Image>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Render Pass Node">
    <Paragraph>
      The top level of the tree is the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderPassNode">IRenderPassNode</PageRef>.
      For draw work, a render pass node is bound to an <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IFrameBuffer">IFrameBuffer</PageRef>
      that describes the window or texture attachments being rendered into. It also records attachment clear values and
      load/store behaviour. For compute work, no framebuffer is bound, but a render pass node is still used to place
      the work in the frame order.
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph>
      Render pass nodes are submitted to the renderer as an ordered list through
      <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderer.SetRenderPasses">SetRenderPasses</PageRef>. That list is the root of
      the render tree for the next submitted frame.
    </Paragraph>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Program Node">
    <Paragraph>
      A <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IProgramNode">IProgramNode</PageRef> groups work that uses the same
      <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IShaderProgram">IShaderProgram</PageRef>. Shader programs define the shader
      stages, shader inputs, and resource names used by child state groups and renderables. Constant state values are
      also associated with the program, because they can affect native shader compilation or pipeline creation.
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph>
      A program node can be the child of more than one render pass node. This allows the same shader and child tree to
      be rendered into multiple passes or windows. Other render tree node types are more restrictive and should be
      treated as having a single active parent.
    </Paragraph>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="State Group Node">
    <Paragraph>
      A <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IStateGroupNode">IStateGroupNode</PageRef> describes fixed-function state
      such as rasterization, depth and stencil tests, culling, polygon fill mode, and blending. It is the usual place to
      put state that is shared by a set of renderables using the same shader program.
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph>
      A state group node is added under one program node. Many state group nodes can be added under the same program
      node, but the same state group node should not be added under multiple parents at the same time. Create another
      node when the same logical content needs different parentage or state.
    </Paragraph>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Renderable Node">
    <Paragraph>
      A <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderableNode">IRenderableNode</PageRef> is the final draw node. It binds
      vertex attributes and optional index data to the shader inputs, selects the primitive mode, and may use instance
      or indirect drawing settings. A renderable is the render tree node that most closely maps to a draw call.
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph>
      A renderable node is added under one state group node. Many renderables can be added under the same state group,
      but a renderable cannot be the child of more than one parent concurrently. If the same geometry needs to appear in
      two branches of the render tree, create a second renderable node that references the same buffers and shader input
      IDs.
    </Paragraph>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Shader Resources">
    <Paragraph>
      Shader resources such as state values, state buffers, data arrays, texel arrays, textures, and texture samplers
      can be bound at different levels of the render tree. Shared values are usually bound high in the tree, such as on
      a default state object or state group node. More specific values can be bound on a renderable node. When a
      renderable is drawn, the more specific binding overrides the inherited binding for the same shader resource ID.
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph>
      Resource names should normally be resolved from the shader program once during setup. Store the returned IDs and
      use those IDs when changing bindings or values. This keeps the render loop independent from text lookups and makes
      resource binding failures easier to detect early.
    </Paragraph>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Summary">
    <Paragraph>
      To recap the basic purpose of each node:
    </Paragraph>
    <List>
      <ListEntry>The render pass node describes the output target and pass order.</ListEntry>
      <ListEntry>The program node describes the shader program used by child work.</ListEntry>
      <ListEntry>The state group node describes fixed-function state and shared resource bindings.</ListEntry>
      <ListEntry>The renderable node describes the geometry, topology, and draw settings.</ListEntry>
    </List>
    <Paragraph>
      Nodes can be added, removed, and modified while building future frames. When <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderer.StartNewFrame">StartNewFrame</PageRef>
      is called, the current tree state is latched for drawing and subsequent changes apply to later frames.
    </Paragraph>
  </Section>
  <Paragraph>
    Next page, <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.Concepts.HelloWorld">Hello World</PageRef>
  </Paragraph>
</XMLDocContent>
