<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<XMLDocContent PageName="cobalt.graphics.Concepts.Shaders" Title="Shaders" xmlns="http://www.cobaltrenderer.com/schema/XMLDocSchema.xsd">
  <Paragraph>
    <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.Welcome">Home</PageRef> ->
    Shaders
  </Paragraph>
  <Section Title="Shaders">
    <Paragraph>
      Shaders are small programs which run on the graphics device. They describe the programmable portions of the
      rendering or compute pipeline, such as transforming vertices, generating fragments, expanding geometry, or running
      general compute work. In Cobalt, shader code is loaded into an <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IShaderProgram">IShaderProgram</PageRef>,
      compiled, reflected, and then attached to an <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IProgramNode">IProgramNode</PageRef>
      in the render tree.
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph>
      Cobalt supports multiple shader code formats, however HLSL is the recommended source language for new shader code.
      In practice, HLSL has become the de facto high-level shader source language for cross-API renderer work. It is the
      native language for Direct3D, is treated as a first-class Vulkan shader source language through the DXC compiler
      and SPIR-V, and is widely used as "the" shader language across the real-time rendering industry today. Major
      engines reflect this: Unreal Engine material graphs are compiled from HLSL-backed material expressions and allow
      custom HLSL code, while Unity documents HLSL as the language used for shader programs and compiles that code to
      the target graphics APIs.
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph>
      Using HLSL as the authoring language also gives access to a broad set of shader features, including structures,
      arrays, structured buffers, byte address buffers, append and consume buffers, and interlocked atomic operations.
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph>
      GLSL, SPIR-V assembly, and binary SPIR-V are also useful formats, particularly when integrating with external
      shader toolchains. In portable application code however, HLSL is generally the simplest long-term choice because a
      single shader source style can be used across all renderer back ends.
    </Paragraph>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Program Shape">
    <Paragraph>
      A graphics shader program must provide a vertex shader and a fragment shader. A geometry shader can be added when
      the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDevice.Feature">GeometryShaders feature</PageRef> is supported by
      the device and enabled when the renderer is created. A compute shader program contains only a compute shader, and
      requires the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDevice.Feature">ComputeShaders feature</PageRef>.
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph>
      It is usually better to build a smaller number of general-purpose shader programs and control their behaviour with
      state values, state buffers, textures, and resource arrays, rather than creating a very large number of specialised
      shader programs. Changing shader programs changes significant pipeline state. On modern APIs this commonly maps to
      changing pipeline state objects, and on older APIs it can require substantial driver-side validation and state
      restoration. Where practical, group draw calls by shader program and use uniform state to select material options,
      lighting modes, and debug views.
    </Paragraph>
    <Code Language="HLSL"><![CDATA[uniform float4 overrideColor;
uniform bool useOverrideColor;

struct FragmentInput
{
    float4 color : COLOR0;
};

float4 main(FragmentInput input) : SV_TARGET0
{
    return useOverrideColor ? overrideColor : input.color;
}]]></Code>
    <Paragraph>
      This approach is not a rule that every possible shader should be merged into one program. Expensive branches,
      different resource layouts, and very different rendering techniques may justify separate shader programs. The
      important guideline is to avoid shader program changes for trivial differences that can be represented clearly as
      state.
    </Paragraph>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Names Not Registers">
    <Paragraph>
      Cobalt does not require applications to assign texture slots, sampler slots, constant buffer registers, or
      descriptor binding numbers in shader source code. The shader program is reflected after compilation, and the
      application resolves the resource names it cares about into opaque IDs such as <TypeRef>TextureId</TypeRef>,
      <TypeRef>SamplerId</TypeRef>, <TypeRef>StateValueId</TypeRef>, <TypeRef>StateBufferId</TypeRef>, and
      <TypeRef>ResourceArrayId</TypeRef>.
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph>
      Names are the public contract between shader code and application code. They are easier to read, easier to review,
      and easier to validate than numeric binding slots. This is the same reason ordinary programming languages name
      variables and functions rather than expecting the programmer to manually remember opaque numeric addresses.
    </Paragraph>
    <Code Language="HLSL"><![CDATA[uniform Texture2D baseColorTexture;
uniform SamplerState baseColorTexture_CombinedSampler;
uniform float4 materialTint;

struct FragmentInput
{
    float2 texCoord : TEXCOORD0;
};

float4 main(FragmentInput input) : SV_TARGET0
{
    return baseColorTexture.Sample(baseColorTexture_CombinedSampler, input.texCoord) * materialTint;
}]]></Code>
    <Code Language="C++"><![CDATA[TextureId baseColorTextureId = shaderProgram->GetTextureId("baseColorTexture");
StateValueId materialTintId = shaderProgram->GetStateValueId("materialTint");

stateGroupNode->BindTextureWithCombinedSampler(baseColorTextureId, baseColorTexture.get(), baseColorSampler.get());
stateGroupNode->SetStateValue(materialTintId, V4Float32(1.0f, 0.8f, 0.7f, 1.0f));]]></Code>
    <Paragraph>
      Resolve these names once during setup, store the IDs, and reuse those IDs when updating render tree state. It is
      valid to call <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IShaderProgram.GetTextureId">GetTextureId</PageRef> and the
      related lookup methods repeatedly, but there is no reason to resolve text strings every frame when the result can
      be cached as part of material, pass, or shader setup data.
    </Paragraph>
    <Note Type="Important">
      <Paragraph>
        Explicit HLSL register annotations or GLSL binding decorations should not be used as the application-facing
        binding model. Cobalt may rewrite binding locations while converting and compiling shader code for the target
        renderer. The stable binding contract is the reflected resource name and the ID returned by the
        <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IShaderProgram">IShaderProgram</PageRef>.
      </Paragraph>
    </Note>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Entry Point Names">
    <Paragraph>
      The default shader entry point name is <TypeRef>main</TypeRef>. Several shader source structures also allow a
      custom entry point name to be supplied when the shader stage is loaded. This is useful when multiple entry points
      are stored in one source file, or when shader code is generated from a shared library of helper functions.
    </Paragraph>
    <Code Language="HLSL"><![CDATA[float4 SolidColorVertex(float3 position : position) : SV_POSITION
{
    return float4(position, 1.0f);
}]]></Code>
    <Code Language="C++"><![CDATA[shaderProgram->LoadShaderStage(
    IShaderProgram::ShaderStage::Vertex,
    ShaderSourceInfoHLSL(vertexShaderCode, "SolidColorVertex"));]]></Code>
    <Paragraph>
      HLSL, SPIR-V assembly, and binary SPIR-V source structures expose entry point name constructors. MSL source
      structures also carry entry point metadata for renderers which accept MSL. GLSL source shaders use the GLSL
      <TypeRef>main</TypeRef> entry point. Already compiled bytecode formats such as DXBC and DXIL have already selected
      the entry point during offline compilation.
    </Paragraph>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Shader Resources">
    <Paragraph>
      Cobalt maps common shader resource constructs onto renderer API objects. Simple global uniform values are exposed
      as state values and are set through <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IStateContainer.SetStateValue">SetStateValue</PageRef>.
      Named constant buffers are exposed as state buffers and are bound through <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IStateContainer.BindStateBuffer">BindStateBuffer</PageRef>.
    </Paragraph>
    <Code Language="HLSL"><![CDATA[uniform float4 drawColor;

cbuffer CameraState
{
    row_major float4x4 viewProjection;
    float4 cameraPosition;
};]]></Code>
    <Code Language="C++"><![CDATA[StateValueId drawColorId = shaderProgram->GetStateValueId("drawColor");
StateBufferId cameraStateId = shaderProgram->GetStateBufferId("CameraState");

stateGroupNode->SetStateValue(drawColorId, V4Float32(1.0f, 0.0f, 0.0f, 1.0f));
stateGroupNode->BindStateBuffer(cameraStateId, cameraStateBuffer.get(), cameraPageNo);]]></Code>
    <Paragraph>
      Texture resources map to the relevant <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.ITextureBuffer">ITextureBuffer</PageRef>
      and <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.ITextureSampler">ITextureSampler</PageRef> types. Combined image samplers
      are the most portable approach. In HLSL, define the texture and sampler with the same base name, and suffix the
      sampler with <TypeRef>_CombinedSampler</TypeRef>. Separate texture and sampler resources can be used when the
      <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDevice.Feature">SeparateTextureSamplers feature</PageRef> is supported
      and enabled, but this is not portable to OpenGL renderers.
    </Paragraph>
    <Code Language="HLSL"><![CDATA[uniform Texture2D colorTexture;
uniform SamplerState colorTexture_CombinedSampler;

float4 SampleColor(float2 texCoord)
{
    return colorTexture.Sample(colorTexture_CombinedSampler, texCoord);
}]]></Code>
    <Paragraph>
      Buffer resources used for large structured data map to resource arrays. HLSL <TypeRef>StructuredBuffer</TypeRef>,
      <TypeRef>RWStructuredBuffer</TypeRef>, <TypeRef>AppendStructuredBuffer</TypeRef>,
      <TypeRef>ConsumeStructuredBuffer</TypeRef>, <TypeRef>ByteAddressBuffer</TypeRef>, and
      <TypeRef>RWByteAddressBuffer</TypeRef> map to <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IDataArray">IDataArray</PageRef>.
      HLSL <TypeRef>Buffer</TypeRef> and <TypeRef>RWBuffer</TypeRef> map to <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.ITexelArray">ITexelArray</PageRef>.
      Resource arrays require the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDevice.Feature">ResourceArrays feature</PageRef>.
    </Paragraph>
    <Code Language="HLSL"><![CDATA[struct Particle
{
    float4 position;
    float4 color;
};

StructuredBuffer<Particle> inputParticles;
RWStructuredBuffer<Particle> outputParticles;

[numthreads(64, 1, 1)]
void main(uint3 threadId : SV_DispatchThreadID)
{
    Particle particle = inputParticles[threadId.x];
    particle.position.xyz += float3(0.0f, 1.0f, 0.0f);
    outputParticles[threadId.x] = particle;
}]]></Code>
    <Paragraph>
      HLSL interlocked atomic operations are supported for the resource types where the target shader model and renderer
      back end support them. A common use is incrementing counters or writing indirect draw arguments from a compute
      shader through an <TypeRef>RWByteAddressBuffer</TypeRef>.
    </Paragraph>
    <Code Language="HLSL"><![CDATA[RWByteAddressBuffer visibleDrawCount;

[numthreads(64, 1, 1)]
void main(uint3 threadId : SV_DispatchThreadID)
{
    uint oldDrawCount = 0;
    visibleDrawCount.InterlockedAdd(0u, 1u, oldDrawCount);
}]]></Code>
    <Note Type="Important">
      <Paragraph>
        Interlocked operations provide atomic updates, but they are not a general replacement for shader memory barriers
        or careful work ordering. If a shader algorithm depends on memory visibility between threads or dispatches, use
        the synchronization constructs required by the shader language and target renderer.
      </Paragraph>
    </Note>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Structured State and Arrays">
    <Paragraph>
      State values and state buffer members can be declared as structures, arrays, arrays of structures, and nested
      structures. Cobalt reflects each leaf state value by name. Structure member access uses dot notation, and each
      ordinary array level in the reflected name is represented with <TypeRef>[]</TypeRef>.
    </Paragraph>
    <Code Language="HLSL"><![CDATA[struct MaterialLayer
{
    float4 tint;
    float roughness;
};

uniform MaterialLayer materialLayers[4];]]></Code>
    <Code Language="C++"><![CDATA[StateValueId layerTintId = shaderProgram->GetStateValueId("materialLayers[].tint");
StateValueId layerRoughnessId = shaderProgram->GetStateValueId("materialLayers[].roughness");

stateGroupNode->SetStateValue(layerTintId, V4Float32(1.0f, 0.8f, 0.6f, 1.0f), 2);
stateGroupNode->SetStateValue(layerRoughnessId, V1Float32(0.35f), 2);]]></Code>
    <Paragraph>
      The same naming pattern applies when arrays are nested inside structures, and when structures contain arrays of
      other structures. One array index is supplied for each <TypeRef>[]</TypeRef> in the reflected name.
    </Paragraph>
    <Code Language="HLSL"><![CDATA[struct Light
{
    float4 position;
    float4 color;
};

struct LightCluster
{
    Light lights[8];
    float exposureByView[2][4];
};

uniform LightCluster clusters[3];]]></Code>
    <Code Language="C++"><![CDATA[StateValueId lightColorId = shaderProgram->GetStateValueId("clusters[].lights[].color");
stateGroupNode->SetStateValue(lightColorId, V4Float32(1.0f, 0.4f, 0.2f, 1.0f), 1, 5);

StateValueId exposureId = shaderProgram->GetStateValueId("clusters[].exposureByView[]");
size_t flattenedExposureIndex = (1 * 4) + 3;
stateGroupNode->SetStateValue(exposureId, V1Float32(0.75f), 1, flattenedExposureIndex);]]></Code>
    <Paragraph>
      These examples set values directly through a state container. State buffers use the same reflected member names
      after their layout is loaded from the shader; the lookup is performed on the state buffer or state buffer layout
      instead of directly on the shader program.
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph>
      HLSL declarations such as <TypeRef>float exposureByView[2][4]</TypeRef> or
      <TypeRef>float weights[2][4][6]</TypeRef> are arrays of arrays. Cobalt supports them only when the
      <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IGraphicsDevice.Feature">ShaderArraysOfArrays feature</PageRef> is supported
      by the device and enabled when the renderer is created. In practice, it is only the legacy OpenGL 3.3 renderer
      where this feature may not be supported. For reflection however, the array-of-array portion is flattened into a
      single one-dimensional array entry. The reflected name contains one <TypeRef>[]</TypeRef> for the flattened
      multidimensional array, and the application supplies a single flattened index for that portion.
    </Paragraph>
    <Code Language="HLSL"><![CDATA[uniform float weights[2][4][6];]]></Code>
    <Code Language="C++"><![CDATA[StateValueId weightsId = shaderProgram->GetStateValueId("weights[]");

size_t firstIndex = 1;
size_t secondIndex = 2;
size_t thirdIndex = 3;
size_t flattenedIndex = (firstIndex * (4 * 6)) + (secondIndex * 6) + thirdIndex;

stateGroupNode->SetStateValue(weightsId, V1Float32(1.0f), flattenedIndex);]]></Code>
    <Paragraph>
      The rightmost HLSL array index moves fastest in the flattened index calculation. For example,
      <TypeRef>weights[1][2][3]</TypeRef> in a <TypeRef>float weights[2][4][6]</TypeRef> declaration becomes
      <TypeRef>(1 * 4 * 6) + (2 * 6) + 3</TypeRef>.
    </Paragraph>
    <Note Type="Important">
      <Paragraph>
        Prefer single-dimensional arrays for new shader state unless multidimensional HLSL syntax is genuinely clearer.
        For example, <TypeRef>float weights[48]</TypeRef> is easier to reflect, easier to index from application code,
        and does not require the <TypeRef>ShaderArraysOfArrays</TypeRef> feature. If arrays of arrays are used, keep the
        flattening formula beside the shader declaration or wrap it in a small helper so the shader and application
        agree on the same indexing convention.
      </Paragraph>
    </Note>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Supported Stages and Constructs">
    <Paragraph>
      The following shader stages and constructs are part of the current Cobalt shader model:
    </Paragraph>
    <List>
      <ListEntry>Vertex shaders are supported for graphics programs.</ListEntry>
      <ListEntry>Fragment shaders are supported for graphics programs.</ListEntry>
      <ListEntry>Geometry shaders are supported when the <TypeRef>GeometryShaders</TypeRef> device feature is supported and enabled.</ListEntry>
      <ListEntry>Compute shaders are supported when the <TypeRef>ComputeShaders</TypeRef> device feature is supported and enabled.</ListEntry>
      <ListEntry>Texture 1D, 2D, 3D, cube, 1D array, 2D array, and cube array sampling are supported through the matching Cobalt texture and sampler types. Cube texture arrays require the <TypeRef>TextureCubeArray</TypeRef> device feature.</ListEntry>
      <ListEntry>Global state values, named constant buffers, arrays, structures, arrays of structures, nested structures, vectors, and matrices are supported. Arrays of arrays require the <TypeRef>ShaderArraysOfArrays</TypeRef> device feature and are flattened for reflection.</ListEntry>
      <ListEntry>Structured data buffers and typed texel buffers are supported through <TypeRef>IDataArray</TypeRef> and <TypeRef>ITexelArray</TypeRef> when the <TypeRef>ResourceArrays</TypeRef> device feature is supported and enabled.</ListEntry>
      <ListEntry>HLSL append, consume, read-write structured buffer, byte address buffer, and interlocked atomic operations are supported where the relevant resource array and shader model support is available.</ListEntry>
    </List>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Unsupported Constructs">
    <Paragraph>
      Some shader language features are deliberately outside the current Cobalt renderer abstraction. They may be
      available in one underlying graphics API, but cannot currently be used as portable Cobalt shader code.
    </Paragraph>
    <List>
      <ListEntry>Hull, domain, and tessellation shader stages are not supported and are not planned for the current renderer interface.</ListEntry>
      <ListEntry>Mesh shader and task or amplification shader stages are not currently represented by <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IShaderProgram.ShaderStage">IShaderProgram.ShaderStage</PageRef>. Mesh shader support is planned for a future renderer interface update.</ListEntry>
      <ListEntry>Ray tracing shader stages and acceleration structure types are not supported by the renderer interface.</ListEntry>
      <ListEntry>GLSL rectangle texture and sampler types, such as <TypeRef>sampler2DRect</TypeRef>, are not supported. Use normalised-coordinate 1D, 2D, 3D, cube, or array texture types instead.</ListEntry>
      <ListEntry>HLSL <TypeRef>RWTexture*</TypeRef> resources and GLSL storage image resources are not supported as image resources. Use <TypeRef>RWStructuredBuffer</TypeRef>, <TypeRef>RWByteAddressBuffer</TypeRef>, or <TypeRef>RWBuffer</TypeRef> backed by <TypeRef>IDataArray</TypeRef> or <TypeRef>ITexelArray</TypeRef> where writable shader data is required.</ListEntry>
      <ListEntry>Comparison samplers and shadow samplers are not exposed by <TypeRef>ITextureSampler</TypeRef>. Perform explicit comparison logic in shader code when this behaviour is required.</ListEntry>
      <ListEntry>Programmable point sizes other than one pixel are not supported portably. Cobalt treats point size as one pixel where the target API requires a point size output.</ListEntry>
      <ListEntry>Explicit register numbers, descriptor sets, and binding decorations are not supported as the application-facing binding contract. Resolve shader resources by name instead.</ListEntry>
    </List>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Further Reading">
    <Paragraph>
      The following external references provide useful background for Cobalt's shader recommendations:
    </Paragraph>
    <List>
      <ListEntry>Microsoft HLSL reference: <URL>https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/win32/direct3dhlsl/dx-graphics-hlsl-reference</URL></ListEntry>
      <ListEntry>Khronos Vulkan guide on HLSL and DXC: <URL>https://docs.vulkan.org/guide/latest/hlsl.html</URL></ListEntry>
      <ListEntry>Khronos SPIRV-Cross project: <URL>https://github.com/KhronosGroup/SPIRV-Cross</URL></ListEntry>
      <ListEntry>Unity manual introduction to writing shaders in HLSL and ShaderLab: <URL>https://docs.unity3d.com/Manual/SL-ShadingLanguage.html</URL></ListEntry>
      <ListEntry>Unity manual for writing HLSL shader programs: <URL>https://docs.unity3d.com/Manual/SL-ShaderPrograms.html</URL></ListEntry>
      <ListEntry>Unreal Engine material node documentation describing HLSL-backed materials: <URL>https://dev.epicgames.com/documentation/en-us/unreal-engine/using-the-main-material-node-in-unreal-engine</URL></ListEntry>
      <ListEntry>Unreal Engine custom material expressions for custom HLSL code: <URL>https://dev.epicgames.com/documentation/en-us/unreal-engine/custom-material-expressions-in-unreal-engine</URL></ListEntry>
      <ListEntry>Microsoft Direct3D 12 pipeline state overview: <URL>https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/win32/direct3d12/managing-graphics-pipeline-state-in-direct3d-12</URL></ListEntry>
      <ListEntry>AMD RDNA performance guide, especially the pipeline state object guidance: <URL>https://gpuopen.com/learn/rdna-performance-guide/</URL></ListEntry>
      <ListEntry>NVIDIA guidance on avoiding redundant and expensive OpenGL state changes: <URL>https://docs.nvidia.com/gameworks/content/technologies/mobile/gles2_perf_maximize_gpu.htm</URL></ListEntry>
      <ListEntry>Microsoft HLSL atomic functions reference: <URL>https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/win32/direct3d11/direct3d-11-advanced-stages-cs-atomic-functions</URL></ListEntry>
    </List>
  </Section>
  <Paragraph>
    Next page, <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.Concepts.BestPractices">Best Practices</PageRef>
  </Paragraph>
</XMLDocContent>
