<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<XMLDocContent PageName="cobalt.graphics.Concepts.ThreadingModel" Title="Threading Model" xmlns="http://www.cobaltrenderer.com/schema/XMLDocSchema.xsd">
  <Paragraph>
    <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.Welcome">Home</PageRef> ->
    Threading Model
  </Paragraph>
  <Section Title="Threading Model">
    <Paragraph>
      The Cobalt Renderer API has some thread safety guarantees, however it does not offer complete thread safety for
      all operations in all circumstances. As a guiding rule, a given object should only be built on one thread, or have
      its modifications externally synchronized. IE, don't create an <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.ITextureBuffer2D">ITextureBuffer2D</PageRef>
      and call <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.ITextureBuffer.SetInitialData">SetInitialData</PageRef> on one thread, then call
      <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.ITextureBuffer.AllocateMemory">AllocateMemory</PageRef> on another. In this
      case, you would need to externally synchronize. When following this guidance, operations are thread safe, with
      the following notable exceptions:
    </Paragraph>
    <List>
      <ListEntry>
        <TypeRef>Binding/unbinding resources.</TypeRef>
        While calls to resource binding methods like <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IStateContainer.BindTexture">BindTexture</PageRef>
        and <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IStateContainer.BindResourceArray">BindResourceArray</PageRef> can be
        made on separate nodes concurrently, it is currently unsafe to call methods which modify the resource binding
        state on a single node concurrently. This may be changed in the future.
      </ListEntry>
      <ListEntry>
        <TypeRef>Modifying state values.</TypeRef>
        While calls to state methods like <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IStateContainer.SetStateValue">SetStateValue</PageRef>
        and <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IStateContainer.ResetStateValue">ResetStateValue</PageRef> can be made on
        separate nodes concurrently, it is currently unsafe to call methods which modify state values on a single node
        concurrently. This may be changed in the future.
      </ListEntry>
      <ListEntry>
        <TypeRef>Modifying IRenderableNode state.</TypeRef>
        It is currently unsafe to modify the vertex/index buffer bindings for the same <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderableNode">IRenderableNode</PageRef>
        concurrently from two different threads. As this can only be done before an <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderableNode">IRenderableNode</PageRef>
        is first added to the render tree, this will not typically be an issue, and is treated as a case of building an
        object. Some updates can be performed after an <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderableNode">IRenderableNode</PageRef>
        has been built and is in use however, such as through <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderableNode.SetVertexCount">SetVertexCount</PageRef>.
        Torn states may be created if this occurs concurrently from multiple threads, so the modification of an
        <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderableNode">IRenderableNode</PageRef> should be externally synchronized.
      </ListEntry>
    </List>
    <Paragraph>
      Despite the threading rules given above, there is one important synchronization rule within the scope of a single
      renderer. The <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderer.StartNewFrame">StartNewFrame</PageRef> method must be
      called in complete exclusion to all other calls on that renderer and all objects created from it. No other renderer
      API call in that object tree should be in progress when <TypeRef>StartNewFrame</TypeRef> is called, and no other
      call should begin until it returns. This allows the renderer to latch a coherent frame boundary efficiently.
      Synchronization helpers to make this rule easier to follow are described below.
    </Paragraph>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Window System Calls">
    <Paragraph>
      Native window systems often impose their own threading requirements. Calls that bind or resize platform windows,
      such as <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IFrameBuffer.BindWindow">BindWindow</PageRef> and
      <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IFrameBuffer.NotifyWindowResized">NotifyWindowResized</PageRef>, must be made
      on the UI thread required by the active platform or window framework. The exact UI-thread dispatch mechanism is
      application-specific.
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph>
      These calls still belong to the renderer object tree. If they can occur while another thread is advancing frames,
      they must be synchronized with <TypeRef>StartNewFrame</TypeRef> in the same way as other renderer calls.
    </Paragraph>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Synchronization Helpers">
    <Paragraph>
      To assist with synchronization requirements, the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.ReadWriteMutex">ReadWriteMutex</PageRef>
      helper class provides a reference implementation of a mutex that allows multiple concurrent readers and a single
      exclusive writer. Pending write lock attempts take priority over later read lock requests, which helps a render
      thread acquire the exclusive frame-advance lock without being starved by update threads.
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph>
      Applications are free to use a different locking scheme. If the application design guarantees that no renderer API
      calls can overlap <TypeRef>StartNewFrame</TypeRef>, no additional external synchronization is required.
    </Paragraph>
  </Section>
  <Paragraph>
    Next page, <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.Concepts.AllocationModel">Allocation Model</PageRef>
  </Paragraph>
</XMLDocContent>
