<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<XMLDocContent PageName="cobalt.marshalling.IMarshalTarget" Title="IMarshalTarget" xmlns="http://www.cobaltrenderer.com/schema/XMLDocSchema.xsd">
  <Section Title="Overview">
    <Paragraph>
      The <TypeRef>IMarshalTarget</TypeRef> family provides the low-level target-side interface used by the marshalling library to write decomposed data
      back into a bound object after it has crossed the assembly boundary. The concrete helper class <PageRef PageName="cobalt.marshalling.MarshalTarget">MarshalTarget</PageRef>
      derives from these interfaces and is what the public output marshal helpers normally create internally.
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph>
      Like the source-side interface, the exact member set varies by specialization. The available methods are shaped by the type being marshalled and by
      the C++ language features available when the code is compiled.
    </Paragraph>
  </Section>

  <Section Title="Member Families">
    <SubSection Title="Marshalling methods">
      <Paragraph>
        Target specializations provide methods that accept decomposed data and write it into the bound object. Depending on the type, this may include
        whole-object marshalling, individual element updates, appends, range writes, and move-enabled overloads.
      </Paragraph>
    </SubSection>
    <SubSection Title="Container metadata">
      <Paragraph>
        STL container specializations provide size, capacity, empty, clear, and resize-style methods where those concepts are meaningful for the bound
        type.
      </Paragraph>
    </SubSection>
    <SubSection Title="Element access">
      <Paragraph>
        Specializations for indexed types expose element-based setter methods so that a marshaller can update a single element in-place without rebuilding
        the entire container.
      </Paragraph>
    </SubSection>
  </Section>

  <Section Title="Usage">
    <Paragraph>
      Application code normally does not create <TypeRef>IMarshalTarget</TypeRef> objects directly. The class exists to support the internals of the higher
      level marshal helpers, and the public target wrapper <PageRef PageName="cobalt.marshalling.MarshalTarget">MarshalTarget</PageRef> should be
      preferred whenever direct use is required.
    </Paragraph>
  </Section>

  <Section Title="See also">
    <PageRefList>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.marshalling.MarshalTarget">MarshalTarget</PageRefListEntry>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.marshalling.MarshalOut">Marshal::Out</PageRefListEntry>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.marshalling.MarshalInOut">Marshal::InOut</PageRefListEntry>
    </PageRefList>
  </Section>
</XMLDocContent>
