<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<XMLDocContent PageName="cobalt.graphics.VertexAttribute.PerformanceHint" Title="PerformanceHint enumeration" xmlns="http://www.cobaltrenderer.com/schema/XMLDocSchema.xsd">
  <Paragraph>
    <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.Welcome">Home</PageRef> ->
    <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.VertexAttribute">VertexAttribute</PageRef> ->
    PerformanceHint
  </Paragraph>
  <Section Title="Description">
    <Paragraph>
      The <TypeRef>PerformanceHint</TypeRef> enumeration provides CPU and GPU read/write usage hints for vertex attribute data. The hints are supplied when a vertex attribute object is constructed.
    </Paragraph>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Members">
    <EnumMemberList>
      <EnumMemberListEntry Name="Default">
        Uses the renderer default storage and synchronization behaviour for this resource.
      </EnumMemberListEntry>
      <EnumMemberListEntry Name="ReadNever">
        Indicates that the application does not expect to read the resource from the CPU after creation or update.
      </EnumMemberListEntry>
      <EnumMemberListEntry Name="ReadRarely">
        Indicates that CPU reads are possible but uncommon, allowing the renderer to favour GPU efficient storage.
      </EnumMemberListEntry>
      <EnumMemberListEntry Name="ReadOften">
        Indicates that the resource may be read frequently by the CPU, allowing the renderer to choose storage or staging behaviour suited to repeated readback.
      </EnumMemberListEntry>
      <EnumMemberListEntry Name="ReadFlagsMask">
        Masks the CPU read behaviour bits. This value is intended for validation and bitwise operations rather than direct selection.
      </EnumMemberListEntry>
      <EnumMemberListEntry Name="WriteNever">
        Indicates that the application does not expect to write new CPU data after initial contents are established.
      </EnumMemberListEntry>
      <EnumMemberListEntry Name="WriteRarely">
        Indicates that CPU writes are possible but uncommon, allowing the renderer to favour storage that is efficient for normal GPU use.
      </EnumMemberListEntry>
      <EnumMemberListEntry Name="WriteOften">
        Indicates that the application expects frequent CPU updates, allowing the renderer to use upload paths suited to repeated writes.
      </EnumMemberListEntry>
      <EnumMemberListEntry Name="WriteFlagsMask">
        Masks the CPU write behaviour bits. This value is intended for validation and bitwise operations rather than direct selection.
      </EnumMemberListEntry>
    </EnumMemberList>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="See also">
    <PageRefList>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.VertexAttribute.Constructor">VertexAttribute.Constructor</PageRefListEntry>
    </PageRefList>
  </Section>
</XMLDocContent>
