<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<XMLDocContent PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderPassNode.EnableAttachmentMultiSamplingResolution" Title="EnableAttachmentMultiSamplingResolution method" xmlns="http://www.cobaltrenderer.com/schema/XMLDocSchema.xsd">
  <Paragraph>
    <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.Welcome">Home</PageRef> ->
    <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderPassNode">IRenderPassNode</PageRef> ->
    EnableAttachmentMultiSamplingResolution
  </Paragraph>
  <Section Title="Description">
    <Paragraph>
      The <TypeRef>EnableAttachmentMultiSamplingResolution</TypeRef> method is used when multisample anti-aliasing
      (MSAA) is being used. This method sets up a task to resolve the target multisampled framebuffer attachment. A
      resolve operation takes a multisampled framebuffer attachment, and performs the appropriate averaging to output a
      resolved version with a single sample per pixel to a target texture.
    </Paragraph>
    <Note Type="Important">
      <Paragraph>
        This operation is only valid for <TypeRef>IRenderPassNode</TypeRef> objects which are bound to an
        <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IFrameBuffer">IFrameBuffer</PageRef> object which have texture targets.
        Window surfaces cannot make use of multisample anti-aliasing.
      </Paragraph>
    </Note>
    <Note Type="Important">
      <Paragraph>
        Only a single resolve operation can be defined for a given source framebuffer attachment per render pass.
        Calling the <TypeRef>EnableAttachmentMultiSamplingResolution</TypeRef> method for a framebuffer attachment that
        has previously had a resolve target set will replace the previous resolve operation.
      </Paragraph>
    </Note>
    <Note Type="Warning">
      <Paragraph>
        When a render pass is disabled using the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderPassNode.SetIsEnabled">SetIsEnabled</PageRef>
        method, multisample resolve operations don't execute either. Where you are conditionally enabling render passes
        for a frame, it may be appropriate to use empty render passes that you leave enabled to perform attachment
        resolve operations. Empty render passes still perform resolve operations, as long as the render pass has not
        been disabled.
      </Paragraph>
    </Note>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Usage">
    <Code Language="C++"><![CDATA[void EnableAttachmentMultiSamplingResolution(IFrameBuffer::AttachmentType attachmentType, size_t attachmentIndex, size_t resolveAttachmentIndex = std::numeric_limits<size_t>::max());]]></Code>
    <SubSection Title="Argument list">
      <ArgumentList>
        <ArgumentListEntry Type="IFrameBuffer::AttachmentType!cobalt.graphics.IFrameBuffer.AttachmentType" Name="type">
          The type of the target framebuffer attachment
        </ArgumentListEntry>
        <ArgumentListEntry Type="size_t" Name="index">
          The index of the framebuffer attachment within the selected attachment type, to use as a source for the
          resolve operation.
        </ArgumentListEntry>
        <ArgumentListEntry Type="size_t" Name="index">
          The index of the target framebuffer resolve attachment within the selected attachment type. If this index is
          left at its default value, the resolve attachment index will take the source attachment index as the resolve
          attachment index too.
        </ArgumentListEntry>
      </ArgumentList>
    </SubSection>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="See also">
    <PageRefList>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderPassNode">IRenderPassNode</PageRefListEntry>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.IFrameBuffer">IFrameBuffer</PageRefListEntry>
    </PageRefList>
  </Section>
</XMLDocContent>
