<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<XMLDocContent PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderPassNode.SetAttachmentClearData" Title="SetAttachmentClearData method" xmlns="http://www.cobaltrenderer.com/schema/XMLDocSchema.xsd">
  <Paragraph>
    <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.Welcome">Home</PageRef> ->
    <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderPassNode">IRenderPassNode</PageRef> ->
    SetAttachmentClearData
  </Paragraph>
  <Section Title="Description">
    <Paragraph>
      The <TypeRef>SetAttachmentClearData</TypeRef> method instructs the renderer to clear the specified framebuffer
      target with the supplied data when this pass begins rendering. If a clear operation has not been defined,
      framebuffer attachments have undefined content for regions that have not been drawn to previously in the current
      frame.
    </Paragraph>
    <Note Type="Important">
      <Paragraph>
        Several overloads are provided to supply clear data in different data formats. All of them will work for any
        attachment target, and the type doesn't need to match the storage format used for the attachment. To make things
        simpler for the application however, and to avoid precision issues where unusual values are used, it is best to
        use the overload that most closely matches the actual storage format. Also note that where an attachment has
        less than four vector components, the supplied values in the excess vector components will be ignored.
      </Paragraph>
    </Note>
    <Note Type="Important">
      <Paragraph>
        Clearing framebuffer attachments does incur a performance penalty, so it's advisable to avoid clearing buffers
        where possible. If you have a compositing pass for example which is guaranteed to generate new content for every
        fragment, a clear operation would not be required. In cases where only part of the image is being populated
        however, or for special buffers such as depth buffers, at least one clear operation should generally be defined
        per frame.
      </Paragraph>
    </Note>
    <Note Type="Warning">
      <Paragraph>
        When a render pass is disabled using the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderPassNode.SetIsEnabled">SetIsEnabled</PageRef>
        method, attachment clear operations don't execute either. Where you are conditionally enabling render passes for
        a frame, it may be appropriate to use empty render passes that you leave enabled at the start of your frame to
        perform attachment clear operations. Empty render passes still perform clear operations, as long as the render
        pass has not been disabled.
      </Paragraph>
    </Note>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Usage">
    <Code Language="C++"><![CDATA[void SetAttachmentClearData(IFrameBuffer::AttachmentType type, size_t index, const V4Float32& data);
void SetAttachmentClearData(IFrameBuffer::AttachmentType type, size_t index, const V4Int32& data);
void SetAttachmentClearData(IFrameBuffer::AttachmentType type, size_t index, const V4UInt32& data);]]></Code>
    <SubSection Title="Argument list">
      <ArgumentList>
        <ArgumentListEntry Type="IFrameBuffer::AttachmentType!cobalt.graphics.IFrameBuffer.AttachmentType" Name="type">
          The type of the target framebuffer attachment
        </ArgumentListEntry>
        <ArgumentListEntry Type="size_t" Name="index">
          The index of the target framebuffer attachment within the selected attachment type
        </ArgumentListEntry>
        <ArgumentListEntry Type="V4Float32/V4Int32/V4UInt32" Name="data">
          The values to use to fill the target framebuffer attachment
        </ArgumentListEntry>
      </ArgumentList>
    </SubSection>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="See also">
    <PageRefList>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderPassNode">IRenderPassNode</PageRefListEntry>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.IFrameBuffer">IFrameBuffer</PageRefListEntry>
    </PageRefList>
  </Section>
</XMLDocContent>
