<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<XMLDocContent PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderPassNode" Title="IRenderPassNode interface" xmlns="http://www.cobaltrenderer.com/schema/XMLDocSchema.xsd">
  <Paragraph>
    <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.Welcome">Home</PageRef> ->
    IRenderPassNode
  </Paragraph>
  <Section Title="Declaration">
    <Code Language="C++"><![CDATA[class IRenderPassNode;]]></Code>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Description">
    <Paragraph>
      The <TypeRef>IRenderPassNode</TypeRef> interface represents the lowest level node in the rendering tree. This node
      is responsible for providing all the content and state involved in a single logical render pass during the
      rendering process, however most of this content and state information comes from child nodes. The only direct
      responsibility the <TypeRef>IRenderPassNode</TypeRef> object has is to specify the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IFrameBuffer">IFrameBuffer</PageRef>
      object which will be used when performing draw operations and various settings associated with it, and to define
      the list of child <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IProgramNode">IProgramNode</PageRef> objects to draw, with an
      optional <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IDefaultState">IDefaultState</PageRef> object associated with each
      <TypeRef>IProgramNode</TypeRef>.
    </Paragraph>
    <Paragraph>
      In addition to specifying the framebuffer to use, the <TypeRef>IRenderPassNode</TypeRef> also defines whether
      content in the framebuffer should be cleared when this render pass is bound during rendering, through the
      <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderPassNode.SetAttachmentClearData">SetAttachmentClearData</PageRef>
      method. It is also possible to configure whether existing content in the framebuffer must be preserved when the
      render pass begins, or whether the written content must be preserved after it completes using the
      <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderPassNode.SetAttachmentLoadStoreBehavior">SetAttachmentLoadStoreBehavior</PageRef>
      method. The render pass node is also used when multisample anti-aliasing (MSAA) is in use, with multisample
      framebuffer attachments being able to be resolved to single-sample textures when the render pass completes,
      through the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderPassNode.EnableAttachmentMultiSamplingResolution">EnableAttachmentMultiSamplingResolution</PageRef>
      method.
    </Paragraph>
    <Note Type="Important">
      <Paragraph>
        The <TypeRef>IRenderPassNode</TypeRef> node is unique on the render tree, in that it contains child nodes which
        are allowed to be added to the render tree more than once. This can allow simple duplication of large areas of
        the scene, such as when drawing to multiple windows, without the need to create separate scene nodes for each
        version. This is done by providing an associated <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IDefaultState">IDefaultState</PageRef>
        object for a <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IProgramNode">IProgramNode</PageRef> child node, which provides
        default bindings and state values which are used for all content under the <TypeRef>IProgramNode</TypeRef>. By
        varying these defaults for each use, it is possible to reuse content with different view and projection matrices
        for example, or potentially a wide variety of state settings which affect the way the content is drawn.
      </Paragraph>
      <Paragraph>
        Where different shader programs are required, perhaps for techniques such as shadow generation, it would still
        generally be necessary to create separate scene nodes for these cases, however <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderableNode">IRenderableNode</PageRef>
        objects are free to share the underlying <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IIndexBuffer">IIndexBuffer</PageRef>
        and <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IVertexBuffer">IVertexBuffer</PageRef> objects which contain the scene
        data, so redefining the scene nodes themselves will not lead to a significant increase in system or graphics
        memory usage.
      </Paragraph>
    </Note>
    <Note Type="Warning">
      <Paragraph>
        An <TypeRef>IFrameBuffer</TypeRef> object must be bound to an <TypeRef>IRenderPassNode</TypeRef> in order for
        the node to be ready for use in the rendering tree. It is an error to attach an <TypeRef>IRenderPassNode</TypeRef>
        to the render tree where no <TypeRef>IFrameBuffer</TypeRef> has been bound, however it is permitted to change
        the bound <TypeRef>IFrameBuffer</TypeRef> while the node is attached to the tree.
      </Paragraph>
    </Note>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Enumerations">
    <TypeMemberList>
      <TypeMemberListEntry Name="AttachmentLoadBehavior" TypeCategory="Enumeration" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderPassNode.AttachmentLoadBehavior" Visibility="Public">
        Specifies whether previous attachment contents must be preserved when the render pass begins.
      </TypeMemberListEntry>
      <TypeMemberListEntry Name="AttachmentStoreBehavior" TypeCategory="Enumeration" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderPassNode.AttachmentStoreBehavior" Visibility="Public">
        Specifies whether final attachment contents must be preserved when the render pass completes.
      </TypeMemberListEntry>
    </TypeMemberList>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Members">
    <SubSection Title="Initialization methods">
      <FunctionMemberList>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="Delete" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderPassNode.Delete">
          Schedules the object for deletion. After calling this method, the object will be destroyed after the current
          frame completes drawing.
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
      </FunctionMemberList>
    </SubSection>
    <SubSection Title="Child node methods">
      <FunctionMemberList>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="AddChildNode" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderPassNode.AddChildNode">
          Adds the specified <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IProgramNode">IProgramNode</PageRef> as a child of this
          node, with an optional associated <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IDefaultState">IDefaultState</PageRef>
          object.
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="AddChildNodes" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderPassNode.AddChildNodes">
          Adds the specified set of <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IProgramNode">IProgramNode</PageRef> objects as
          children of this node, with optional associated <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IDefaultState">IDefaultState</PageRef>
          objects for each one.
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="RemoveChildNode" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderPassNode.RemoveChildNode">
          Removes the specified <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IProgramNode">IProgramNode</PageRef> as a child of this node
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="RemoveChildNodes" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderPassNode.RemoveChildNodes">
          Removes the specified set of <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IProgramNode">IProgramNode</PageRef> objects as children of this node
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="RemoveAllChildNodes" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderPassNode.RemoveAllChildNodes">
          Removes all current <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IProgramNode">IProgramNode</PageRef> child nodes
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="SetChildNodes" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderPassNode.SetChildNodes">
          Sets the specified set of <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IProgramNode">IProgramNode</PageRef> objects as
          children of this node, removing any existing child nodes which may have been previously added.
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
      </FunctionMemberList>
    </SubSection>
    <SubSection Title="Framebuffer methods">
      <FunctionMemberList>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="BindFrameBuffer" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderPassNode.BindFrameBuffer">
          Binds the specified <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IFrameBuffer">IFrameBuffer</PageRef> to this node
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="SetAttachmentLoadStoreBehavior" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderPassNode.SetAttachmentLoadStoreBehavior">
          Allows the application to relax requirements around whether framebuffer contents must be retained before or after this render pass is drawn
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="SetAttachmentClearData" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderPassNode.SetAttachmentClearData">
          Instructs the renderer to clear the specified framebuffer target with the supplied data when this pass begins rendering
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="RemoveAttachmentClearData" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderPassNode.RemoveAttachmentClearData">
          Removes a previously added instruction to clear a framebuffer target when this pass begins rendering
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="EnableAttachmentMultiSamplingResolution" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderPassNode.EnableAttachmentMultiSamplingResolution">
          Instructs the renderer to resolve a multisampled framebuffer attachment down to the specified single-sampled
          target texture when this render pass completes rendering
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="DisableAttachmentMultiSamplingResolution" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderPassNode.DisableAttachmentMultiSamplingResolution">
          Removes a multisampled framebuffer attachment resolution operation previously set by the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderPassNode.EnableAttachmentMultiSamplingResolution">EnableAttachmentMultiSamplingResolution</PageRef>
          method.
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
      </FunctionMemberList>
    </SubSection>
    <SubSection Title="Enabled state methods">
      <FunctionMemberList>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="SetIsEnabled" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderPassNode.SetIsEnabled">
          Sets the enabled state of this node to the specified value. If this node is disabled, it will be ignored
          during rendering. No child nodes will be evaluated, and no defined framebuffer operations will occur.
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
      </FunctionMemberList>
    </SubSection>
    <SubSection Title="Debug methods">
      <FunctionMemberList>
        <FunctionMemberListEntry Visibility="Public" Name="SetDebugName" PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderPassNode.SetDebugName">
          Sets a debug name for this render pass node, where supported by the renderer and native graphics API.
        </FunctionMemberListEntry>
      </FunctionMemberList>
    </SubSection>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="See also">
    <PageRefList>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.IProgramNode">IProgramNode</PageRefListEntry>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.IStateGroupNode">IStateGroupNode</PageRefListEntry>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderableNode">IRenderableNode</PageRefListEntry>
    </PageRefList>
  </Section>
</XMLDocContent>
