<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<XMLDocContent PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderer.WaitForOutputCaptureComplete" Title="WaitForOutputCaptureComplete method" xmlns="http://www.cobaltrenderer.com/schema/XMLDocSchema.xsd">
  <Paragraph>
    <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.Welcome">Home</PageRef> ->
    <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderer">IRenderer</PageRef> ->
    WaitForOutputCaptureComplete
  </Paragraph>
  <Section Title="Description">
    <Paragraph>
      This method performs the same synchronization as the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderer.WaitForDrawComplete">WaitForDrawComplete</PageRef>
      method, however it will wait not just until the draw process is complete, but also until any attached framebufffer
      output capture objects have received data, as well as any other intermediate data outputs generated during the
      draw process. Without calling this method, the renderer will only make captured output available after a call is
      made to <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderer.StartNewFrame">StartNewFrame</PageRef>, however if the
      application calls <TypeRef>WaitForOutputCaptureComplete</TypeRef> it explicitly synchronizes the application with
      the capture process in the renderer, and as a result the renderer will make captured output immediately available
      to the application when this method returns. This data will also continue to be available after <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderer.StartNewFrame">StartNewFrame</PageRef>
      is called like it normally would, but calling the <TypeRef>WaitForOutputCaptureComplete</TypeRef> method gives the
      application earlier access to this data, and importantly allows it do to so without starting a new frame drawing.
    </Paragraph>
    <Note Type="Important">
      <Paragraph>
        It is perfectly valid to call this method even if no <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IFrameBufferOutput">IFrameBufferOutput</PageRef>,
        <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IDataArrayOutput">IDataArrayOutput</PageRef>, or <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.ITexelArrayOutput">ITexelArrayOutput</PageRef>
        objects have been attached to any framebuffers used in the last draw operation.
      </Paragraph>
    </Note>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Usage">
    <Code Language="C++"><![CDATA[void WaitForOutputCaptureComplete();]]></Code>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="See also">
    <PageRefList>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderer">IRenderer</PageRefListEntry>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderer.WaitForDrawComplete">IRenderer.WaitForDrawComplete</PageRefListEntry>
    </PageRefList>
  </Section>
</XMLDocContent>
