<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<XMLDocContent PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderer.WaitForDrawComplete" Title="WaitForDrawComplete method" xmlns="http://www.cobaltrenderer.com/schema/XMLDocSchema.xsd">
  <Paragraph>
    <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.Welcome">Home</PageRef> ->
    <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderer">IRenderer</PageRef> ->
    WaitForDrawComplete
  </Paragraph>
  <Section Title="Description">
    <Paragraph>
      Calls to this method will block until the current draw process is complete. Note that this method doesn't
      guarantee that the result of drawing operations have been made visible on the screen yet, or that any requested
      framebuffer output capture processes are complete, but those operations will at least be pending or in progress at
      the time this method returns.
    </Paragraph>
    <Note Type="Important">
      <Paragraph>
        Renderers are not required to make the results of any draw operations visible on screen until either the <TypeRef>WaitForDrawComplete</TypeRef>
        method is called, or the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderer.WaitForOutputCaptureComplete">WaitForOutputCaptureComplete</PageRef>
        or <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderer.StartNewFrame">StartNewFrame</PageRef> methods are called. While
        some renderers may make the image available without any of these methods being called, this is not guaranteed.
        If you are not rendering continuously, you must call this method before idling to ensure the image is made
        visible.
      </Paragraph>
    </Note>
    <Note Type="Warning">
      <Paragraph>
        Calling this method doesn't make the results of any framebuffer output capture operations from the draw process
        that was just completed available to the application. If your application needs to read captured framebuffer
        output from the frame which was just drawn, it must either call the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderer.WaitForOutputCaptureComplete">WaitForOutputCaptureComplete</PageRef>
        method, or wait until the next frame begins drawing from a call to <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderer.StartNewFrame">StartNewFrame</PageRef>.
    </Paragraph>
    </Note>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Usage">
    <Code Language="C++"><![CDATA[void WaitForDrawComplete();]]></Code>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="See also">
    <PageRefList>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderer">IRenderer</PageRefListEntry>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderer.WaitForOutputCaptureComplete">IRenderer.WaitForOutputCaptureComplete</PageRefListEntry>
    </PageRefList>
  </Section>
</XMLDocContent>
