<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<XMLDocContent PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderer.StartNewFrame" Title="StartNewFrame method" xmlns="http://www.cobaltrenderer.com/schema/XMLDocSchema.xsd">
  <Paragraph>
    <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.Welcome">Home</PageRef> ->
    <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderer">IRenderer</PageRef> ->
    StartNewFrame
  </Paragraph>
  <Section Title="Description">
    <Paragraph>
      The renderer usually has two concurrent processes running: the build phase and the draw phase. Calling the
      <TypeRef>StartNewFrame</TypeRef> waits for the current draw process to complete, then rolls the build state over
      into the draw state and starts a new frame drawing. Once a frame has been submitted for drawing, the application
      cannot modify it in any way. Any attempts to modify the state of any objects only affect the build state, which
      will be used to define the contents of the next frame which is drawn after the <TypeRef>StartNewFrame</TypeRef>
      method is called again.
    </Paragraph>
    <Note Type="Important">
      <Paragraph>
        When the renderer is first created, it starts in build mode. This means scene content can be set and modified
        straight away. The first time <TypeRef>StartNewFrame</TypeRef> is called, a new frame will be submitted for
        drawing.
      </Paragraph>
    </Note>
    <Note Type="Warning">
      <Paragraph>
        Note that no state changes are permitted while this method is being called, on any objects which have been
        created by this renderer instance. Although all objects provided by the renderer are thread safe under normal
        operation, a call to the <TypeRef>StartNewFrame</TypeRef> method must be performed exclusively. External
        synchronization to ensure that no other operations are in progress or are initiated when this method is being
        called is the responsibility of the application. The renderer SDK provides the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.ReadWriteMutex">ReadWriteMutex</PageRef>
        type to assist with synchronization. Please see the section on the <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.Concepts.ThreadingModel">Threading Model</PageRef>
        for more information.
      </Paragraph>
    </Note>
    <Note Type="Important">
      <Paragraph>
        If the previous frame has not finished drawing yet, this method will block until the frame has been fully
        rendered. If your application has a fixed set of changes that must make it into each frame, where no new frames
        can be drawn until all the changes are performed, and no more changes are required once they are complete, it is
        sufficient to call <TypeRef>StartNewFrame</TypeRef> after each set of changes to advance the drawing process. If
        however your application has updates that run independently from the draw process, and merely need to be
        submitted as transactions which make it into whichever frame is currently being drawn, it is recommended to
        call <PageRef PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderer.WaitForDrawComplete">WaitForDrawComplete</PageRef> first to
        ensure that all pending draw tasks have been completed. This will ensure that <TypeRef>StartNewFrame</TypeRef>
        blocks for the minimal amount of time, which is important as no render state changes can be performed while this
        method is executing.
      </Paragraph>
    </Note>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="Usage">
    <Code Language="C++"><![CDATA[void StartNewFrame();]]></Code>
  </Section>
  <Section Title="See also">
    <PageRefList>
      <PageRefListEntry PageName="cobalt.graphics.IRenderer">IRenderer</PageRefListEntry>
    </PageRefList>
  </Section>
</XMLDocContent>
